<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>text on Enter The Exit</title>
    <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/tags/text/</link>
    <description>Recent content in text on Enter The Exit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:24:14 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/tags/text/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/growth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:24:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/growth/</guid>
      <description>Seed When we see a model in life, we generally tend to try, more or less consciously, to become more like it. Because we see something in this person that inspires us, or that feels so right, that we just want to take even just a piece of that for ourselves. Be it a value, a point of view, a character trait, many things can trigger this phenomenon.
Is it his unbreakable determination?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter feeling</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/winter_feeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 13:54:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/winter_feeling/</guid>
      <description>Introduction: It&amp;rsquo;s cold outside. Your nose is hardened by the cold and it starts running. Your fingertips are numb and your gloves don&amp;rsquo;t keep the warmth enough. Your breath creates wonderful volutes that your eyes, squinting through the wind, sometimes contemplate. And you find in your pockets, the cold metal that would deliver you. Your fingers have trouble holding it straight and turning it, but it clicks, it opens, and here you are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Head in the clouds</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/head_in_the_clouds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 02:54:08 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/head_in_the_clouds/</guid>
      <description>&amp;emsp;&amp;ldquo;Yes, it may sound stupid but it&amp;rsquo;s been like, years I&amp;rsquo;ve had that problem! And I tried mostly everything.&amp;rdquo;
&amp;emsp;&amp;ldquo;Everything?&amp;rdquo;
She wasn&amp;rsquo;t very interested, but polite, according to the social conventions she learned. But she finished her daily tasks long ago, so she didn&amp;rsquo;t need to worry.
&amp;emsp;&amp;ldquo;Well, I went to see my doctor first, he said I should get a better pillow. I have an amazing pillow now. I sleep much better, that&amp;rsquo;s nice, I even stopped snoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:57:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/supernovae/</guid>
      <description>&amp;emsp;Encore un débat, je sens déjà que ça pétille en moi. Ça gronde à chaque virgule, ça détonne à chaque point. Je navigue dans cette logique, ces prémisses délicates, ces hypothèses fertiles. Le flot de mes pensées vire gré des implications. Les écueils sauront s&amp;rsquo;occuper des sophismes jetés par dessus bord, et chaque biais mis à jour se verra mourir au soleil. Au dessus de moi, c&amp;rsquo;est un feu d&amp;rsquo;artifice qui jaillit à chaque inférence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celcius</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 15:27:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</guid>
      <description>Intro First of all there is one difficult word in there : hearth which designates the floor of the fireplace. To appreciate this poem, I recommend you to look in the vague (outdoors if possible) and do not fix anything at all, just blurry vision, for like 30 seconds. No, not right now, at the end of the intro. Take a deep breath. Now look away and then don&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Tiny Dragon</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:08:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</guid>
      <description>Text I have a dragon in my room. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Show me your dragon&amp;rdquo; but I cannot. Sadly, it is small, very very small. And it is fast, very very fast. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Then how do you know it exists ?&amp;rdquo; Well it&amp;rsquo;s simple. Sometimes I feel like I tripped over something but no cable, no furniture just a perfectly flat floor, as if it just carelessly bumped into me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>