<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>poetry on Enter The Exit</title>
    <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/tags/poetry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in poetry on Enter The Exit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:57:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/tags/poetry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Supernovae</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/supernovae/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:57:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/supernovae/</guid>
      <description>&amp;emsp;Encore un débat, je sens déjà que ça pétille en moi. Ça gronde à chaque virgule, ça détonne à chaque point. Je navigue dans cette logique, ces prémisses délicates, ces hypothèses fertiles. Le flot de mes pensées vire gré des implications. Les écueils sauront s&amp;rsquo;occuper des sophismes jetés par dessus bord, et chaque biais mis à jour se verra mourir au soleil. Au dessus de moi, c&amp;rsquo;est un feu d&amp;rsquo;artifice qui jaillit à chaque inférence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Celcius</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 15:27:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</guid>
      <description>Intro First of all there is one difficult word in there : hearth which designates the floor of the fireplace. To appreciate this poem, I recommend you to look in the vague (outdoors if possible) and do not fix anything at all, just blurry vision, for like 30 seconds. No, not right now, at the end of the intro. Take a deep breath. Now look away and then don&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by anything.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Tiny Dragon</title>
      <link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:08:44 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</guid>
      <description>Text I have a dragon in my room. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Show me your dragon&amp;rdquo; but I cannot. Sadly, it is small, very very small. And it is fast, very very fast. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Then how do you know it exists ?&amp;rdquo; Well it&amp;rsquo;s simple. Sometimes I feel like I tripped over something but no cable, no furniture just a perfectly flat floor, as if it just carelessly bumped into me.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>