<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Enter The Exit</title>
		<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Enter The Exit</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:27:56 +0200</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>Paradigm change</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/paradigmchange/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:27:56 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/paradigmchange/</guid>
			<description>Disclaimer: &amp;emsp;This &amp;ldquo;rant&amp;rdquo; is not about whether one diet is better than another on any aspect, it&amp;rsquo;s about how we treat these different diets. Does not mean I&amp;rsquo;m not biased toward one or the other, and hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t be too problematic to you.
Problem setup &amp;emsp;When you go to the restaurant, you need to check that your food is gluten free, lactose free, meat free, cruelty free, fish free, nut free or even other qualifiers.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h3 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer:</h3>

<p>&emsp;This &ldquo;rant&rdquo; is not about whether one diet is better than another on any aspect, it&rsquo;s about how we treat these different diets. Does not mean I&rsquo;m not biased toward one or the other, and hopefully it won&rsquo;t be too problematic to you.</p>

<h2 id="problem-setup">Problem setup</h2>

<p>&emsp;When you go to the restaurant, you need to check that your food is gluten free, lactose free, meat free, cruelty free, fish free, nut free or even other qualifiers. It is usual nowadays that a restaurand would have a section dedicated for one or multiple of these specificities. In this &ldquo;essay&rdquo; I will try to challenge the very idea of assigning these kind of labels to food.</p>

<p>&emsp;People have different and sometimes incompatible diets. Above all else, this is a fact that we must simply respect for the simple reason that everyone should be free to choose to not eat something. This is the assumption upon which the rest is built.</p>

<p>&emsp;Putting these tags on a menu is a way to indicate to certain specific persons if they will be able to eat this particular dish.</p>

<h2 id="proposal">Proposal</h2>

<p>&emsp;Wouldn&rsquo;t it be much more sensible to indicate it the other way around?</p>

<p>&lsquo;Why&rsquo;, you&rsquo;d say, &lsquo;it works well like that.&rsquo;<br/>
Glad you asked.<br/>
<u>Let&rsquo;s take an example:</u><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cfffdb;">Hey buddy you remember this dude that we didn&rsquo;t meet in college?</span><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cff5ff">What?</span><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cfffdb">You know, the guy that doesn&rsquo;t have long hair, who happen to not wear baseball caps?</span></p>

<p><u>Alternate version:</u><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cfffdb">Hey buddy you remember this dude from high school?</span><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cff5ff">Which one?</span><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cfffdb">You know, the guy with blond short hair that was taller than you?</span></p>

<p>&emsp;Obviously one is more sensible than the other. Because we describe things by what they are, not by what they aren&rsquo;t.
When things are mutually exclusive it works very well to use one or the other.</p>

<p><u>Example:</u><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cfffdb">Hi buddy, how&rsquo;s it going?</span><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cff5ff">Not bad, not bad, you?</span><br/>
<u>And:</u><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cfffdb">Hi buddy how&rsquo;s it going?</span><br/>
&ndash; <span style="color:#cff5ff">Fairly fine, and you?</span></p>

<p>&emsp;Here, no problem because you are either going fine or not. There&rsquo;s no mistake. This is not so similar with food.
Indeed you either do want or do not want to eat something. Yet because people have different opinions for each and every foodstuff (in their good right), it is only fair to let them decide if it&rsquo;s okay by saying what&rsquo;s inside and not selecting some choices about what&rsquo;s not inside.<br/></p>

<h2 id="argument">Argument</h2>

<p>&emsp;An interesting argument is scalability. If you say what&rsquo;s inside, everyone can make its choice. By selecting some subgroups and targeting the &ldquo;main focus&rdquo; of this subgroup, every person that has slightly different views or needs cannot necesarily know whether it&rsquo;s good for them. One person, even not knowing any other subgroup&rsquo;s preferences, should be able to choose the food they are okay with.</p>

<p>Another example came to my mind:</p>

<p>&emsp;Let&rsquo;s say you own a tavern, and there are more than fifty races, all with different eating habits, all with different preferences. Hobgobelins, orcs, humans, elves, dwarves, ifrits, kobolds and more! (it&rsquo;s a very inclusive tavern, and also modern in the sense that they would be at our technology level)<br/>
Because you are a careful owner who wants everyone to get the food they want, you need to label the food in some fashion so that orcs won&rsquo;t eat the leaves that they can&rsquo;t digest, elves won&rsquo;t eat meat and kobolds won&rsquo;t eat the ashes of the ifrits (kobolds are dumb).</p>

<p>Will you say &ldquo;hobgobelin, orc, dwarf can eat this dish&rdquo;, or &ldquo;Fox-person-suitable food&rdquo; ?
No of course, it&rsquo;s stupid, you just declare what&rsquo;s inside, and every person can ask for the dish they want.</p>

<p>&emsp;And yet the crazy per-category labelling is happening.
Gluten free, lactose free, ketogenic, vegetarian or vegan or even pescetarian or more.
The scalability really shines here, because once the labelling per ingredient is done, it is enough for all possible habits.</p>

<h2 id="counter-argument">Counter Argument</h2>

<p>&emsp;A counter argument would be that some ingredients of importance may appear sooner or later. This is true, gluten is not an obvious thing to include in the ingredient list. Yet lactose intolerance and gluten intolerance are like allergies in this regard. We can expect that there would be a list of common (and there is!) of common allergens. This list may be updated as the relevant authority sees it fit.</p>

<p>&emsp;Of course if only different tastes were involved, it would not be so necessary.
But there are medical, ethical, environmental and maybe more reasons to consume or not a given food, and that does not make every food equal.</p>

<p>&emsp;Some may also say that it is already done on the back of the products you buy (this ignores the restaurant problem). Indeed products have their composition written.<br>
Here we are talking about labelling, meaning having a symbol or a group of symbols that would &lsquo;summarize&rsquo; the relevant informations. Basically what is done at the moment.</p>

<p>&emsp;Some eating habits also include in their selection the way the product has been made. Fair trade, vegan (it&rsquo;s not just not consuming animal products but not having anything from animal exploitation). So for instance, coconut seems fine for a vegan. WELL it depends. Some coconut is harvested using monkeys to climb the trees and gather coconuts. Even if the monkey is not being mistreated, he (I say he even for objects sometimes, deal with it) this is not, strictly speaking, vegan. Some vegan would draw different &ldquo;thresholds&rdquo; for these questions, but it&rsquo;s not the topic at hand. <br/>
&emsp;This was a mere tentative to show how being perfectly inclusive seem difficult.</p>

<p>&emsp;Though, technology could help us with for instance a qr code that would link you to the complete info. But this is a complex system.</p>

<h2 id="even-tempered-argument">Even-tempered argument</h2>

<p>I understand the reassuring feeling that you may have if you are intolerant (or allergic) to something and you see &ldquo;thing-free&rdquo; label on the food. This is perfectly understandable when it&rsquo;s a question of life or death. I don&rsquo;t really have anything to say about it. Especially that suing someone for mislabelling is hard when you&rsquo;re dead (even though corpses are fairly hard too).</p>

<h2 id="a-cultural-problem">A cultural problem ?</h2>

<p>&emsp;If in your community, the norm would be to never eat food X (religion is what comes to mind first for me) then the food would be explicitly labeled &ldquo;contains X&rdquo; because this food is &ldquo;not standard&rdquo;.</p>

<p>&emsp;Hence in a society where eating meat is standard, wheat flour is common and milk the base of most sauces, it seems logical that we ended up labelling it this way. So when you enter in a &ldquo;green&rdquo; restaurant, you expect everything to be organic, so nothing is labeled as organic. Some specific foodstuff might not be though and they would specifically point it. Same with a vegetarian-oriented-but-meat-eater-frienly-restaurant. No meat would be what you expect first.</p>

<h2 id="sort-of-an-argument-i-guess">Sort of an argument I guess</h2>

<p>&emsp;But anyway, is this practice of labelling good, is it bad?</p>

<p>On one hand I would say that it&rsquo;s not so important as long as you end up eating what you want.</p>

<p>On the other hand&hellip;</p>

<p><u>Strong opinion ahead:</u><br/>
I repeat what I just said before for clarity.<br/>
disclaimer: is said at the begining that it wasn&rsquo;t about which diet is best, and since here it&rsquo;s heavily opinion based, I will heavily bias the way I present the arguments (that I could have done in a diet-neutral way but choose not to).</p>

<p>It does not make sense to put labels &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo;, &ldquo;vegan&rdquo; or whatever else like that on a menu.
What would make sense is &ldquo;made with x,y,z&rdquo; then you decide whether x,y, or z is a problem to you or not.<br/>
This would dramatically change the mindset.<br/>
&ldquo;this contains meat&rdquo;<br/>
&ldquo;and eggs&rdquo;<br/>
&ldquo;and cheese&rdquo;<br/>
&ldquo;and nuts&rdquo;<br/>
&ldquo;and cow&rsquo;s milk&rdquo;<br/>
&ldquo;and was cooked with butter&rdquo;</p>

<p>&emsp;People would get a much better view of what they are eating. Yes, most people eat meat everyday and close to every meal. I know for I did the same.
And since things are labeled &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo; oh why boy, you&rsquo;re not vegetarian, why would you take this?<br/>
This is damaging. It separates people, as if not being vegetarian makes you unable to appreciate a vegetarian meal.<br/>
&emsp;That is at least how I felt. &ldquo;Oh I&rsquo;ll try this vegetarian thing&rdquo; &ldquo;oh it&rsquo;s not that bad&rdquo;. DUH. It&rsquo;s just the same food, just balanced differently. Even people eating with me would be surprised like &ldquo;oh you&rsquo;re vegetarian&rdquo;. <br/>
&emsp;The very fact that I thought &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll try this vegetarian thing&rdquo; is a problem, it should not feel like it&rsquo;s from another planet. And we make it this way by labelling things with &ldquo;vegan&rdquo;, &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo;.<br/>
It&rsquo;s not for someone who belongs to a group, it&rsquo;s for everyone who&rsquo;s okay with eating that. And people most definitely are because that&rsquo;s what they eat all the time, except we switched one ingredient or two.</p>

<p>This is valid for groups that are fully included one in the others.<br/>
In the sense that <code>$ RV \in VG \in V \in OV \in P \in O$</code> with :
<div class="tableNoBorder">
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="left">symbol name</th>
<th align="left">Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>

<tbody>
<tr>
<td align="left">$O$ omnivore:</td>
<td align="left">almost everything edible</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align="left">$P$ pescetarian:</td>
<td align="left">$O$ minus meat-related products</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align="left">$OV$ ovo-lacto-vegetarian:</td>
<td align="left">$P$ without seafood</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align="left">$V$ vegetarian:</td>
<td align="left">$OV$ without diaries and eggs</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align="left">$VG$ vegan:</td>
<td align="left">$V$ but no animal exploitation at all</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align="left">$RV$ raw vegan:</td>
<td align="left">$VG$ but only raw food</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<div class="tableNoBorder">
<h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion</h2>

<p>&emsp;Both sides have a fairly good argumentation, and I did&rsquo;t give every possible argument.
Looking at these, I opt for the paradigm change. The reason is that this solution would blur the limit of the social transition and social weight to go from $O$ down the chain (I am <strong>not</strong> implying here that further down is best, this is for another time). My reasons for this are the same that made me reflect on my dietary habits.  It is also a good thing in another sense: if more people (the pool of $O$ people is quite big) consume &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo; options, more &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo; options will be available. And one of my reasons for wanting this is obviously that I like having many things to choose from.
</div>
</div>
</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Celcius</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 15:27:37 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</guid>
			<description>Intro First of all there is one difficult word in there : hearth which designates the floor of the fireplace. To appreciate this poem, I recommend you to look in the vague (outdoors if possible) and do not fix anything at all, just blurry vision, for like 30 seconds. No, not right now, at the end of the intro. Take a deep breath. Now look away and then don&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by anything.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="intro">Intro</h2>

<p>First of all there is one difficult word in there : <em>hearth</em> which designates the floor of the fireplace.
To appreciate this poem, I recommend you to look in the vague (outdoors if possible) and do not fix anything at all, just blurry vision, for like 30 seconds. No, not right now, at the end of the intro. Take a deep breath. Now look away and then don&rsquo;t be distracted by anything.</p>

<h2 id="celcius">Celcius</h2>

<div class="centeredBlock">


You know, they say it's warm.<br/>
And they say it warms your heart.<br/>
And even that some people smile.<br/>
But... My thermometer is broken. How can I find out ?<br/><br/>
I tried to remember the warmth of the sun,<br/>
I think I caught sunburns.<br/>
I tried to remember the warmth of the hearth,<br/>
My eyes were lost in the ashes.<br/><br/>
But nothing makes sense.<br/><br/>
Because when I think about it,<br/>
And I find my tears flowing,<br/>
I know there is more.<br/><br/>
You, who knows everything,<br/>
Could you tell me<br/>
The temperature of a hug ?

</div>


<h1 id="manifest">Manifest</h1>

<p>I know, the intro is weird, but I feel like if you just arrive here with all your thoughts and wanting to read quickly the new post of your acquaintance and then be done with it, you&rsquo;re not really in the right mood see why just below.</p>

<h2 id="context">Context</h2>

<p>This poem was made during a fairly dark period of my life. A permanent struggle at the time. I was terribly lacking human contact, be it social or physical (hugs are drugs). I was sick, my mind was barely working. I wanted to share my confusion about how trivial things can become complicated. But in a cute way.</p>

<h2 id="comments">Comments</h2>

<p>Once again, I imagine the character talking to be a little girl (and if it&rsquo;s a mirror of myself, maybe it&rsquo;s the little girl I was always forbidden to be).<br/>
I like the idea of trying to show that things that we take for granted, can be much deeper than at first sight. And for this, what&rsquo;s best than a fresh look on life: children. They look at everything and discover their emotions with the eye of discovery. And from time to time, they point something that we overlooked or had long forgotten.<br/>
Even with that said, I find it kind of childish but not in the right way, I&rsquo;m talking about the writer. It feels clumsy. Also I think there is potential for beautiful imagery here, but it could not go out of his brain. Let&rsquo;s be kind to the sick me.<br/>
I think that &ldquo;temperature of a hug&rdquo; is a beautiful image, and it love it. It&rsquo;s saddening that I left it this way, it could have been so much more. Because I didn&rsquo;t want to ruin this image before reading the poem, I called the poem Celcius.<br/>
Oh by the way here is my inspiration:</p>


<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/3NftUsNp8W0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>


<p>It is from a mobile music game I love tremendously: <a href="https://www.rayark.com/g/deemo/">Deemo</a>. It made me discover the artist: V.K. (and Mili is fantastic as well) The song is indeed called 擁抱的溫度, or Temperature of a hug if, like me, you don&rsquo;t read Chinese.</p>

<h2 id="side-note">Side note</h2>

<p>Here is the background I used for this page (still trying out features!). I took this a while ago, it&rsquo;s a fancy bokeh effect. The person who guesses how I took it gets uuuh, pancakes. No, it&rsquo;s cheatung if I told you already! But I&rsquo;m never out of pancakes to be honest :D. By the way, I find this background way too dim. I need to fiddle with this
<img src="https://i.ibb.co/zxjKBQP/Bubble-Bath.jpg" alt="BubbleBath" /></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Raymarching</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/raymarching/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:20:57 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/raymarching/</guid>
			<description>Introduction I always had a keen interest into fractals, I played quite a fair bit with Apophysis. That&amp;rsquo;s how I created these images:
As you can see, there was also transparency. They look very different on a white or on a black background, you can try (for the first two ones)
Fractals give me a sentiment of infinite complexity, and complexity looks mesmerizing to me. Especially structured complexity, like see how in the Grand-Julian there is usage of symmetry, and also patterns like these circles waving around the red part?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>

<p>I always had a keen interest into fractals, I played quite a fair bit with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apophysis_(software)">Apophysis</a>. That&rsquo;s how I created these images:</p>

<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/DRx1nmv/Grand-Julian.png" alt="Grand-Julian" /></p>

<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/Fgt4nWm/Piatch.png" alt="Piatch" /></p>

<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/th66ZGb/triancore.png" alt="triancore" /></p>

<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/qgdm7br/Triangula.png" alt="Triangula" /></p>

<p>As you can see, there was also transparency. They look very different on a white or on a black background, you can try (for the first two ones)</p>

<p>Fractals give me a sentiment of infinite complexity, and complexity looks mesmerizing to me. Especially structured complexity, like see how in the Grand-Julian there is usage of symmetry, and also patterns like these circles waving around the red part? Also the symmetry is only an illusion, because looking carefully, the global idea is the same on both side but it&rsquo;s variating, always redefining itself.
I like that, I just can&rsquo;t help it. It&rsquo;s so abstract, so deep, but at the same time it&rsquo;s just a big fat math equation, tailored by myself to unravel its fierce elegance under the form of an image. <strong>takes a deep breath</strong></p>

<p>So it was really nice, but I had no idea how to render fractals. And I didn&rsquo;t care.</p>

<p>Now the time has come. I&rsquo;ve already written my own (crappy) pathtracer so it cannot be so hard.
I understand how raytracing works. But I never had the chance to learn about ray marching.</p>

<p>So I fiddled with python and found some ressources on internet (where else ?)
I wanted to have as few info as possible, and I wanted to solve all the problems myself.</p>

<h2 id="full-program-in-16-lines">Full program in 16 lines</h2>

<p>Guess what?
It&rsquo;s easy.
I&rsquo;m not joking:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="c1">#this is the object list</span>
<span class="n">o</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb">list</span><span class="p">()</span>
<span class="n">o</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">append</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Sphere</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mf">0.5</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.2</span><span class="p">]))</span>
<span class="n">o</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">append</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Sphere</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">],</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mf">0.1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.4</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.7</span><span class="p">]))</span>
<span class="c1">#setting camera parameters, first position, then point to look at</span>
<span class="n">c</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">Camera</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">15</span><span class="p">],[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">],</span><span class="n">fovy</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">40</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">xres</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">300</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">yres</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">300</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">img</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">np</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">zeros</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="n">xres</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">yres</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">])</span> <span class="c1"># 3channels</span>
<span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">i</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="nb">range</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">xres</span><span class="p">):</span>
    <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">j</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="nb">range</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">yres</span><span class="p">):</span>
        <span class="nb">dir</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">getDirPix</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">cpos</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">pos</span>
        <span class="c1">#index, final pos of the ray</span>
        <span class="n">io</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">rayMarch</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">cpos</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="nb">dir</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">o</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">contrib</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">*</span><span class="mi">3</span>
        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">io</span><span class="o">==-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">:</span>
            <span class="n">contrib</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">np</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">array</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">*</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="k">else</span><span class="p">:</span>
            <span class="n">contrib</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">o</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">io</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">cpos</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="nb">dir</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">img</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">contrib</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Of course there are the <code>rayMarch()</code> function and the <code>Camera</code>.</p>

<h2 id="parallel-with-ray-tracing-and-further-explanations">Parallel with ray tracing and further explanations</h2>

<p>Basically only two things differ from normal ray tracing:</p>

<ul>
<li>intersection function does not really exist anymore</li>
<li>objects are represented by a signed distance function</li>
<li>your ray is litterally taking small steps to go traverse the scene</li>
</ul>

<p>The process goes this way:</p>

<ul>
<li>define objects (like spheres) with SDF corresponding to their parameters (radius, position, color)</li>
<li>choose an origin $O_r$ for your ray (like, not too far not too close)</li>
<li>choose a direction $d$ for your ray (straight on a sphere is good)</li>
</ul>

<p>Here, Rey Marching begins</p>

<ol>
<li>then compute the $SDF(O_r)$ for all objects in your scene</li>
<li>take the minimum of it, let&rsquo;s call it <del>Oscar</del> $msdf$</li>
<li>advance your ray of $msdf$ in the direction d (so it is $newO_r=O_r+msdf$)</li>
<li>then you repeat using the $newO_r$</li>
<li>check if the sdf is EPSILON or less, if it&rsquo;s the case then you intersected, report the color value

<ul>
<li>EPSILON is here for some more tolerance (floating point errors or stuff can happen)</li>
</ul></li>
</ol>

<p>If you do that, you will loop indefinetely so best thing is to impose a hard limit to the distance the ray can travel
Another solution would be to compute the bouding box of the scene (if at all, possible) and to measure the distance from the ray to the farthest point of it. But well, I just use 50, it&rsquo;s a good number.</p>

<p>You can also impose a number of maximum steps, and if the ray is misbehaving, (doing too many small steps) hop, background color</p>

<h2 id="ray-marching-algorithm">Ray Marching algorithm</h2>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="n">EPSILON</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mf">1e-8</span>
<span class="n">LIM</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">256</span>
<span class="n">END</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">50</span>
<span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">rayMarch</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sd</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">o</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="nb">list</span><span class="p">()):</span>
    <span class="s1">&#39;&#39;&#39; sp is starting point, sd is starting direction and o is the list of shapes
</span><span class="s1">    marches in the scene, returns
</span><span class="s1">    * index of Shape intersected
</span><span class="s1">    * last position of ray
</span><span class="s1">    &#39;&#39;&#39;</span>
    <span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">obj</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">d</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">obj</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">o</span><span class="p">]</span>
    <span class="n">v</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb">min</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="n">index</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">index</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">v</span><span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="n">depth</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">v</span>
    <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">0</span>
    <span class="c1">#test against epsilon here and LIM because sometimes it just gets stuck</span>
    <span class="k">while</span> <span class="n">v</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="n">EPSILON</span> <span class="ow">and</span> <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="n">LIM</span><span class="p">:</span>
        <span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">obj</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">d</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">obj</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">o</span><span class="p">]</span>
        <span class="n">v</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb">min</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">index</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">index</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">v</span><span class="p">)</span>
        
        <span class="n">sp</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="n">v</span><span class="o">*</span><span class="n">sd</span>
        <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">+=</span><span class="mi">1</span>
        <span class="c1"># yes I know i compute twice the same stuff,</span>
        <span class="c1"># I added this later and I was too lazy to change the rest </span>
        <span class="n">depth</span><span class="o">+=</span><span class="n">v</span>
        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">depth</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="n">END</span><span class="p">:</span>
            <span class="k">return</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span>
    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">&gt;=</span><span class="n">LIM</span><span class="p">:</span>
        <span class="k">return</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span>
    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">index</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Now, you say, that does not make an image!
Of course we need a camera. But that&rsquo;s maths and all, so let me just say that you give the camera a position to be, a position to look at, and boom, you&rsquo;re set.</p>

<p>Now that we have a camera, we call the very convenient function <code>getPixelDir(i,j)</code> that gives us the direction or the ray</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s say we want a 1080p image, our image is $w=1920$ pixels wide and $h=1080$ pixels high</p>

<ul>
<li>loop $w$ times:

<ul>
<li>loop $h$ times:</li>
<li>$d=getPixelDir(i,j)$ ($i$,$j$ are the current loop number for $w$ and $h$ loops)</li>
<li>$p=getCameraPos$</li>
<li>$color=rayMarch(p,d)$</li>
<li>$img[i,j]=color$</li>
</ul></li>
</ul>

<h2 id="results">Results</h2>

<p>boom done. Do that and, like me, you obtain THIS:</p>

<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/nkQskTc/first.png" alt="img" /></p>

<p>Incredible huh?</p>

<p>Yes, it&rsquo;s shit, but what did you expect? there is no lighting, no bounce of the light. All this is for a real renderer.</p>

<p>okay, let me add the cos term so that it looks like actual balls at least:</p>

<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/PWBG7XZ/3balls.png" alt="img" /></p>

<p>I just wanted to see how it works but now, I need to get on the fractal train.</p>

<p>And I have to say, python sucks! It&rsquo;s so damn slow!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>My Tiny Dragon</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:08:44 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</guid>
			<description>Text I have a dragon in my room. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Show me your dragon&amp;rdquo; but I cannot. Sadly, it is small, very very small. And it is fast, very very fast. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Then how do you know it exists ?&amp;rdquo; Well it&amp;rsquo;s simple. Sometimes I feel like I tripped over something but no cable, no furniture just a perfectly flat floor, as if it just carelessly bumped into me.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<h2 id="text">Text</h2>

<p>I have a dragon in my room. One may ask &ldquo;Show me your dragon&rdquo; but I cannot. Sadly, it is small, very very small. And it is fast, very very fast. One may ask &ldquo;Then how do you know it exists ?&rdquo; Well it&rsquo;s simple. Sometimes I feel like I tripped over something but no cable, no furniture just a perfectly flat floor, as if it just carelessly bumped into me. I regularly sense a peculiar yet very faint smell, like something caught fire. Though after inspection, nothing burnt, no cooking, no worn out cable or electronic device going crazy. It can only be the fiery breath of the dragon, probably roasting its meal. I have no idea about what this dragon eats though. Maybe it picks something from the trash ? Or maybe it steals from the fridge ? I never noticed such a thing, but I suppose such a tiny dragon doesn&rsquo;t need much. A fly or two from time to time may very well be enough for all I know&hellip; One may say &ldquo;Oh but that&rsquo;s nothing, you&rsquo;re probably imagining stuff&rdquo;. I can only tell you what I experience, but I cannot make you experience my feelings. Let me tell you more about the dragon.</p>

<p>When the wind chimes through my shutters and the sky covers itself of its starry blanket as my consciousness fades, I can hear it, I can feel it. Just next to my head, a calm breathing, a warm breeze.
As soon as I try to gather my still sleeping thoughts, it vanishes. I try to place my hand where I felt it but the mattress isn&rsquo;t warmer, the air isn&rsquo;t agitated, it simply disappeared. But it was here.
Once I was sick and I had terrible stomach pain. Going to sleep was awful, I couldn&rsquo;t get rest because of the pain, but couldn&rsquo;t stay awake because I was exhausted.
When the clouds made everything dark and the wind howled its best to free the stars, I lost myself to exhaustion. A soft warmth pressing against my belly, just like a hot stone, perfectly adjusted.
The hard scales heated up by the ardent inner fire of the dragon made for a very regenerating sleep. The sun just began to rise when I noticed that I slept on the back. I never sleep
on the back. I thought it was because of the stomach pain, maybe this position helps. But after testing, the pain is actually more intense when my body is on the back because the whole belly is extended compared to foetal position. I can only think it was to allow the dragon to heal me somehow. My stomach pain was significantly better this day, and although I was not cured, my state was now tolerable.</p>

<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/4j24jxf/DSCF2229.jpg" alt="img" /></p>

<p>I do not need you to believe in my dragon, my dragon is very real for me and I like him very much. I believe he is my friend and in any case I will always welcome him and his friends. But I do not care if someone does not believe in my dragon. You might be a scientist thirsty for knowledge, or a psychologist looking for an interesting case. Maybe you want to capture my dragon and study him, or make me sit and interrogate me. Maybe you just want to prove me I&rsquo;m wrong, that my dragon is nothing but delusions of an imaginative mind. Maybe. But I won&rsquo;t let you kill my dragon.</p>

<p>You are not allowed any experiment. You are not allowed to make me understand what I actually tripped over or that the sound I heard was something else entirely. You are not allowed to make me doubt that the warmth I felt wasn&rsquo;t his. My dragon will live on until he decides to leave.</p>

<h2 id="manifest">Manifest</h2>

<p>The picture is from me, during a trip in Belle-île. One of my first pictures of the stars. My fuji x100s in not made for that, and to be honest, I don&rsquo;t like it so much anymore (the picture, not the camera).
I added it when doing the post, more to see how to put images and figure out a way to put them online easily.</p>

<h3 id="context">Context</h3>

<p>When I wrote this poem I was still active on a forum and there I exchanged with people persuaded by astrology, by Christiannism, by a lot of beliefs that sometimes hurt them more than they help. Some of them were very depressed.</p>

<p>I wanted to share a part of my understanding of this situation.</p>

<p>I feel sorry that they need to go this far in the nonsense to find salvation. Yet, they do feel better, some people find in these something that society, psychiatrists or their job do not offer. And that is not their fault.</p>

<p>And this is very good and I am delighted that they find something that works for them.</p>

<p>Yet they start to build a sentimental, emotional bond with it. And as the little girl (I imagine that, but it&rsquo;s sexist, sorry) will outgrow her enthusiastic imagination, they should also outgrow their beliefs. Not in the sense that they should part with them, in the sense that it is not needed anymore. In the state I saw a lot of people (a lot is actually not even statistically sensible, but it&rsquo;s more than most people dealt with) they were like imprisoned by their beliefs. They could not evolve enough to be able to choose if they wanted to live with or without.
This is saddening.</p>

<p>This is a topic (&ldquo;outgrowing beliefs&rdquo;) that I am fairly sensitive to. I think I have a lot of things to think about on this topic.</p>

<h3 id="comments">Comments</h3>

<p>I decided to share this as-is, without modifications, even if I think I could improve it. (It was written 5 months ago)</p>

<p>I like the way it sounds childish, but the end feels off. It does not feel like a child anymore, and it&rsquo;s more all the frustration that was in me that talked. In some sense, I feel like a gradient of childishness in this poem. Maybe that&rsquo;s good.</p>

<p>Very little rewriting happened (I would definitely use different images instead of twice stars : &ldquo;starry blanket&rdquo;, &ldquo;free the stars&rdquo;)
but at the time I had no intention to publish it, so I did not really care.</p>

<p>I wanted to illustrate how people end up getting into these.. fields? esoterism? I don&rsquo;t really know, but you get it: mostly irrationnal stuff.</p>

<p><strong>Confirmation bias</strong>: Looking for proofs that aren&rsquo;t really there, ignoring all the clues that point in other directions
The stone moment illustrate how vicious life can be at giving you information.</p>

<p>It can look like you got better, but actually the night was just nice and the sleep was in the end of good quality. In any case she would feel better and better. Let&rsquo;s not neglect placebo effect that may very well apply here.</p>

<p>There is also this tendency to not use <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occam%27s_razor">Ockham&rsquo;s razor</a></strong>: she thinks it was to help the dragon heal her that she slept on the back but it could be a misplaced pillow because, while trying to get asleep, she kept moving around, moving pillows, or whatever other reason.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>My First Post</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-first-post/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2019 12:09:06 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
			<description>Bon ben fallait pas s&amp;rsquo;attendre à grand chose, hein! premier post, on fait des tests et tout&amp;hellip; Ahhh c&amp;rsquo;est le texte du lien qui va dans cette boiiiite, je me disais aussi.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bon ben fallait pas s&rsquo;attendre à grand chose, hein!
premier post, on fait des tests et tout&hellip;
<a href="../demotypo/demotypography">Ahhh c&rsquo;est le texte du lien qui va dans cette boiiiite, je me disais aussi.</a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Typography</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/demotypo/demotypography/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:36:33 +0800</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/demotypo/demotypography/</guid>
			<description>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[

<p>Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit, sed do eiusmod tempor incididunt ut labore et dolore magna aliqua. Ut enim ad minim veniam, quis nostrud exercitation ullamco laboris nisi ut aliquip ex ea commodo consequat. Duis aute irure dolor in reprehenderit in voluptate velit esse cillum dolore eu fugiat nulla pariatur. Excepteur sint occaecat cupidatat non proident, sunt in culpa qui officia deserunt mollit anim id est laborum.</p>

<blockquote>
<p>An apple is a sweet, edible fruit produced by an apple tree (Malus pumila). Apple trees are cultivated worldwide, and are the most widely grown species in the genus Malus. The tree originated in Central Asia, where its wild ancestor, Malus sieversii, is still found today. Apples have been grown for thousands of years in Asia and Europe, and were brought to North America by European colonists. Apples have religious and mythological significance in many cultures, including Norse, Greek and European Christian traditions.<sup class="footnote-ref" id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1">1</a></sup></p>
</blockquote>

<hr />

<p>Inline styles：</p>

<p><strong>strong</strong>, <em>emphasis</em>, <strong><em>strong and emphasis</em></strong>,<code>code</code>, <u>underline</u>, <del>strikethrough</del>, 😂🤣, <code>$e^5 \LaTeX $</code>, X^2^, H~2~O, ==highlight==, <a href="https://example.com">Link</a>, and image:</p>

<p><img src="https://picsum.photos/600/400/?random" alt="img" /></p>

<hr />

<p>Headings:</p>

<h1 id="heading-1">Heading 1</h1>

<h2 id="heading-2">Heading 2</h2>

<h3 id="heading-3">Heading 3</h3>

<h4 id="heading-4">Heading 4</h4>

<h5 id="heading-5">Heading 5</h5>

<h6 id="heading-6">Heading 6</h6>

<p>Table:</p>

<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th align="left">Left-Aligned</th>
<th align="center">Center Aligned</th>
<th align="right">Right Aligned</th>
</tr>
</thead>

<tbody>
<tr>
<td align="left">col 3 is</td>
<td align="center">some wordy text</td>
<td align="right">$1600</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align="left">col 2 is</td>
<td align="center">centered</td>
<td align="right">$12</td>
</tr>

<tr>
<td align="left">zebra stripes</td>
<td align="center">are neat</td>
<td align="right">$1</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>

<p>Lists:</p>

<ul>
<li>Unordered list item 1.</li>
<li>Unordered list item 2.</li>
</ul>

<ol class="task-list">
<li>ordered list item 1.</li>
<li>ordered list item 2.

<ul class="task-list">
<li>sub-unordered list item 1.</li>
<li>sub-unordered list item 2.

<ul class="task-list">
<li><label><input type="checkbox" checked disabled class="task-list-item"> something is DONE.</label></li>
<li><label><input type="checkbox" disabled class="task-list-item"> something is NOT DONE.</label></li>
</ul></li>
</ul></li>
</ol>

<p>Syntax Highlighting:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-javascript" data-lang="javascript"><span class="kd">var</span> <span class="nx">num1</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">num2</span><span class="p">,</span> <span class="nx">sum</span>
<span class="nx">num1</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">prompt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Enter first number&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="nx">num2</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nx">prompt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Enter second number&#34;</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="nx">sum</span> <span class="o">=</span> <span class="nb">parseInt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">num1</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="nb">parseInt</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="nx">num2</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="c1">// &#34;+&#34; means &#34;add&#34;
</span><span class="c1"></span><span class="nx">alert</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="s2">&#34;Sum = &#34;</span> <span class="o">+</span> <span class="nx">sum</span><span class="p">)</span>  <span class="c1">// &#34;+&#34; means combine into a string
</span></code></pre></div><div class="footnotes">

<hr />

<ol>
<li id="fn:1">From <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple</a>
 <a class="footnote-return" href="#fnref:1"><sup>[return]</sup></a></li>
</ol>
</div>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
