<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Posts on Enter The Exit</title>
		<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/</link>
		<description>Recent content in Posts on Enter The Exit</description>
		<generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 20:57:09 +0200</lastBuildDate>
		<atom:link href="https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
		
		<item>
			<title>I promise</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/ipromise/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 20:57:09 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/ipromise/</guid>
			<description>a declaration or assurance that one will do something or that a particular thing will happen. Oxford Dictionary
 Honor Before writing became very common, words were used to bind people. &amp;ldquo;You have my word&amp;rdquo; is an expression very similar in meaning to a promise. The word &amp;ldquo;word&amp;rdquo; here implies that the act of saying a binding word or expression, such as &amp;ldquo;I will do X&amp;rdquo; is in itself binding.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<blockquote>
<p>a declaration or assurance that one will do something or that a particular thing will happen. Oxford Dictionary</p>
</blockquote>
<h2 id="honor">Honor</h2>
<p>Before writing became very common, words were used to bind people. &ldquo;You have my word&rdquo; is an expression very similar in meaning to a promise. The word &ldquo;word&rdquo; here implies that the act of saying a binding word or expression, such as &ldquo;I will do X&rdquo; is in itself binding. At this time, what could be called honor would ensures the person would do what he commited to. A person would lack honor when not doing as he said. Honor was important, because people needed to rely on something to assert the trustworthiness of someone. The honor status of people would be known and people knew who to trust.</p>
<p>When writing and contract law became commonplace, honor became unnecessary for trust. Now you trust the paper and the pen, and the system. Honor isn&rsquo;t a thing to protect anymore. (Not that it&rsquo;s a bad thing) Does modern society has a Honor system? That&rsquo;s another debate entirely. We still promise things, but the weight is far lower. Is that true? Maybe the internal moral compass has changed. As far as my experience goes, I didn&rsquo;t live centuries earlier, and I don&rsquo;t know if people were true to their word more than people are today. My experience of today though, is that most promises people made to me ended unmet. I have the feeling that people do not feel strongly tied by the promise. This leads to a heavy distorsion between what we say and what we think of it.</p>
<h2 id="social-contract">Social contract</h2>
<p>What does &ldquo;I promise to do X&rdquo; means to you? Let&rsquo;s say, A says that to B, and assume they are friends not negociating a contract, and cunning is not involved: both are of good faith.
Does it mean that A has to do X, now that it&rsquo;s promised? What should B do or think if A doesn&rsquo;t do X? And what if A tried but didn&rsquo;t succeed?</p>
<p>I suggest looking at it this way. At the start, A and B didn&rsquo;t owe anything to each other. You can replace X by &ldquo;call you tomorrow&rdquo; or &ldquo;will visit you next week&rdquo; or &ldquo;I won&rsquo;t be late&rdquo;.
Then, for whatever reason, A promised to do X to B. This now creates a different relation. B is expecting something of A. This expectation can only have negative outcomes: either X is done and that was expected, it&rsquo;s neutral, either X is not done and B views it negatively.
Even for something small, fairly insignificant, ever if B doesn&rsquo;t really care that X is done, having failed to fulfill a promise changes something.
It changes who A is as a person. A is a little bit more a person whose word is not reliable. B is likely to think less of A regarding trustworthiness, and future promises could be met with a raised eyebrow. This process can very well be unconscious, so no amount of &ldquo;it&rsquo;s okay, I don&rsquo;t care&rdquo; would change it.</p>
<h2 id="i-love-you-darling-i-promise-i-will-never-leave-you">I love you darling, I promise I will never leave you</h2>
<p>In social context, what do promises mean?
What A likely tried to achieve, was to show commitment, or affection toward B. It can show confidence in the ability to do X. It is supposed to leave B to believe &ldquo;X will be taken care of, you can rest assured&rdquo;. A having failed to do X, B went from happy to have someone&rsquo;s help (or anything that X is about), to being disappointed and having to find another way, losing time along the way, or being prepared for X and not having it.</p>
<p>I can see this in social contexts, where promising looks to me like an &ldquo;affection commitment&rdquo;. People don&rsquo;t like uncertainty, so, promising helps alleviate the problem. It&rsquo;s not &ldquo;maybe&rdquo; it&rsquo;s a promise now! Even if in the end, it&rsquo;s unmet, at least the previous feeling of uncertainty has been erased (temporarily). It&rsquo;s a tool to alleviate uncertainty. Especially in insecure couples, where one feels the need to promise to visit every week, or to call or whatever. &ldquo;I promise I will always love you&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s all fun and games until it&rsquo;s a chore. It is also a way to show that they are ready to put the affection/consideration of the other into play. Indeed, failing to meet the expectations is essentially letting the other have the right to judge you for not giving what is owed, albeit more often than not it&rsquo;s socially downplayed, but unconsciously important<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup>.
Why doing that to oneself? More precisely, why bet on one&rsquo;s own future feelings? Promising neverending love doesn&rsquo;t make it happen. (Love should probably be redefined then)</p>
<h2 id="what-to-do-then">What to do then?</h2>
<p>The point is, having promised something is mostly a negative experience. Failing to meet someone&rsquo;s expectations when one initially wanted to is mostly a negative experience.
Even if there is no hard binding, a promise is still a promise and will alter the opinion others have of you, but also the one you have of yourself.</p>
<p>A significantly more sensible approach would be to simply not promise anything. If you want to do it, just do it. Or try. Say you&rsquo;ll try, do your best, that&rsquo;s all. If the other person can&rsquo;t deal with that level of uncertainty, then maybe they have some work on themselves to do.
A promise is an unnecessary source of stress. For some reason, promises have been romanticized. Also, as hard as it might be, when someone asks you to promise something, refuse. For your own good, do not let people ask things from you. If you want to do it, do it. Truth is, promises are really not needed for things to happen.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s not much. Don&rsquo;t put yourself in a position where others expect something from you. (very general (maybe bold) statement, but it&rsquo;s here in the context of promises. Of course, it can be a tool to play with others' expectations, and that&rsquo;s for you to see if you can wield the tool, or if you&rsquo;ll end up being the social instrument.)</p>
<h2 id="the-proof">The &ldquo;proof&rdquo;</h2>
<p>Successfully meeting a promise is rewarding/rewarded. The reward is $R$.<br>
Successfully meeting a promise is difficult and a probability of success can be affected. The probability is $P$.<br>
Unsuccessfully meeting a promise is negatively rewarding/rewarded. The negative reward is $N$.<br>
The Promise is $X$.<br>
The expected reward is $E[X]=RP+N(1-P)$.</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s rephrase.<br>
You&rsquo;re in a casino.<br>
You have a chance $P$ to win the prize.<br>
The prize is $R$.<br>
The entry price in $N$.<br>
The gample is $X$.<br>
The expected reward is $E[X]=RP+N(1-P)$.</p>
<p>A promise is essentially a social gamble. Is it wrong? Not necessarily. One just needs to remember that not playing is often the way to outsmart the system. Especially when odds are not in your favor. The social reward of the promise is actually quite small, but it exists. A small dose of dopamine, probably. The disappointment being mostly unconsious (but orders of magnitude more impactful) it is downweighted by our short-term idiotic brain.</p>
<p>The reality is that odds are always in your favour when you say &ldquo;well, I&rsquo;ll do my best but I don&rsquo;t promise it will be done&rdquo;. Then you have the reward if you succeed. The negative isn&rsquo;t so bad anymore. The other person isn&rsquo;t disappointed. Win-Win.</p>
<p>John Doe</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I did not prove here that the more or less unconscious effect exists and is important. That&rsquo;s a hidden (not so hidden anymore) premise. Do you think that it plays a role? How big is it? The disappointment can be very real but since this case is obvious, I don&rsquo;t talk too much about it. <a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Vide</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/vide/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 05 Oct 2020 20:21:33 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/vide/</guid>
			<description>Parfois je me sens vide. Vide comme un panier à champignons sans champignons.
En fait, je sais pas vraiment comment c&amp;rsquo;est d&amp;rsquo;être vide comme un panier à champignons sans champignons.
Mais je sais ce que c&amp;rsquo;est, ce vide qui me prend. Comme un vers qui n&amp;rsquo;a laissé derrière lui qu&amp;rsquo;une large cavité, là où il y avait mes émotions.
Et soudain, plus rien. Le chaud, le froid m&amp;rsquo;indiffèrent. Le sucré me laisse de marbre.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Parfois je me sens vide. Vide comme un panier à champignons sans champignons.<br>
En fait, je sais pas vraiment comment c&rsquo;est d&rsquo;être vide comme un panier à champignons sans champignons.<br>
Mais je sais ce que c&rsquo;est, ce vide qui me prend. Comme un vers qui n&rsquo;a laissé derrière lui qu&rsquo;une large cavité, là où il y avait mes émotions.<br>
Et soudain, plus rien. Le chaud, le froid m&rsquo;indiffèrent. Le sucré me laisse de marbre.<br>
La perspective du pain grillé beurre-salé-confiture me fait soupirer tant l&rsquo;entreprise semble futile.<br>
Mais ce n&rsquo;est pas grave, ça arrive. Le chocolat chaud peut bien attendre le temps qu&rsquo;il faudra.\</p>
<p>Mais voilà qu&rsquo;un message affectueux ne m&rsquo;arrache plus de sourire.<br>
Que l&rsquo;idée même d&rsquo;ami semble lointaine, brumeuse, fastidieuse presque.<br>
Je me demande qu&rsquo;est-ce que c&rsquo;est ce que ces gens ressentent. Ça semble étranger.<br>
C&rsquo;est peut-être ça finalement les émotions. Un corps étranger que mon système immunitaire parvient parfois à repousser.<br>
Mais en plus du sentiment de vide, quand j&rsquo;ignore cette affection, quand je me rend compte que mon moi est vide d&rsquo;amour, je me sens comme tomber.<br>
Comme une chute libre qui ne commence jamais vraiment, et qui ne s&rsquo;achève que lorsque je porte mon attention ailleurs.<br>
Je sais qu&rsquo;il me manque quelque chose, et ça a l&rsquo;air important.<br>
Des sentiments d&rsquo;affection qui durent des centaines, voir des milliers de jours. Et à ce moment, je ne ressent rien.<br>
Des milliers de grains de poussière.\</p>
<p>Je ne suis plus ici, je ne suis plus humain.<br>
Je n&rsquo;éprouve ni plaisir ni malheur. Je sens que j&rsquo;ai perdu quelque chose.<br>
J&rsquo;évolue dans un banal espace quadridimensionnel. Mes sens ajoutent quelques dimensions, petites, locales.<br>
Et cet espace est à la fois immense et tout à fait étriqué.<br>
Je viens de l&rsquo;espace où les couleurs sont aussi des odeurs qui sont aussi le feu dans tes yeux.<br>
Je viens du monde où les sons serrent le ventre, où les sourires arrachent des larmes, où les mots pèsent mille tonnes.<br>
Des dimensions qui m&rsquo;indiffèrent, bien entendu, je ne perçoit que leur projections sur mon espace. Ça me semble inutile. Dénué d&rsquo;intérêt.\</p>
<p>Je ne suis pas humain.<br>
Je suis un automate guidé par le besoin irrépressible de persister dans ma nature. Manger, boire, dormir.<br>
Je mange, je bois. C&rsquo;est pas l&rsquo;heure de dormir. Mon corps n&rsquo;a besoin de rien. Mon cerveau n&rsquo;a besoin de rien.<br>
Je sais qu&rsquo;il me manque quelque chose, et je tente de comprendre. Vaguement, sans grand intérêt.<br>
Je n&rsquo;ai rien d&rsquo;autre à faire après tout.<br>
Je retrouve de tendres souvenirs qui immanquablement auraient du me plonger en nostalgie.<br>
Pourtant c&rsquo;est bien un visage de marbre qui les accueillis, mais pire encore, un ennui profond.<br>
Qui sont ces étrangers que je reconnais ? Qui est cet homme qui me ressemble trait pour trait ?<br>
L&rsquo;entreprise de compréhension touchait à sa fin.<br>
L&rsquo;ennui gagnait.<br>
Le soleil était sous l&rsquo;horizon,<br>
le lit était froid, mes poils se hérissaient, je contemplais ce fait avec indifférence.\</p>
<p>C&rsquo;est là qu&rsquo;au réveil, après que la brume cérébrale s&rsquo;eût dissipée, je contemplait ma mémoire.<br>
Ais-je imaginé? C&rsquo;est avec l&rsquo;horreur la plus interne que des larmes perlent.<br>
Culpabilité, déception, mais surtout terreur, et si ça revenait?<br>
Et si ça arrivait encore ? Et ceux que j&rsquo;aime ?<br>
Tremblotant, presque fiévreux, les images de leurs visages déçus, blessés, dégoûtés me transpercent, me brûlent.<br>
Accepter mes erreurs, mes défauts, bien doués pour ça.<br>
Mais pendant cette déviance inhumaine, j&rsquo;aurais pu laisser chacun d&rsquo;eux pour mort.<br>
Je suis inhumain. On pardonne aux humains, on pardonne aux animaux. Être inhumain, c&rsquo;est bien pire qu&rsquo;être un animal féroce.<br>
Cette part de moi, est-ce qu&rsquo;elle est pardonnable ?<br>
La culpabilité est acide.<br>
Je les aime, je les aime profondément. Et ça crie dans mon coeur quand je m&rsquo;imagine vide d&rsquo;amour.<br>
Je tremble. J&rsquo;ai froid. J&rsquo;ai peur.<br>
Je redoute le moment où cette antithèse de l&rsquo;humanité reviendra.\</p>
<p>Lilli</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Finally the end</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/finally_the_end/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 23:21:08 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/finally_the_end/</guid>
			<description>Please do not read if you are in depression or in an unstable mental state. Try this one instead: a better read — You know, some other people are like me. I&amp;rsquo;ve met some. We share the same story. You&amp;rsquo;re down, feeling terrible, worthless, you feel there is no salvation to your pitiful soul and you think, you&amp;rsquo;re absolutely certain that you should&amp;rsquo;ve been thrown in a bottomless pit long ago.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h4 id="please-do-not-read-if-you-are-in-depression-or-in-an-unstable-mental-state-try-this-one-instead-a-better-readhttpsluvideriagithubioentertheexitpostswinter_feeling-winter-feeling">Please do not read if you are in depression or in an unstable mental state. Try this one instead: <a href="https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/winter_feeling/" title="Winter Feeling">a better read</a></h4>
<p>— You know, some other people are like me. I&rsquo;ve met some. We share the same story. You&rsquo;re down,
feeling terrible, worthless, you feel there is no salvation to your pitiful soul and you think, you&rsquo;re absolutely certain that you should&rsquo;ve been thrown in a bottomless pit long ago.
This oppressing darkness, strangling your throat, making you think threatening thoughts, desire derelict daydreaming and fear fathomless fantasy. 
For some it&rsquo;s a terrible emptiness like a worm eating all your pleasure, your joy to only let an abysmal void behind.
Some of us decide to take action. Some do it very quickly, at the peak of their pain, or out of fear that it becomes greater even.
I very well understand the extent to which some people are pushed by their sick mind, and they have all my compassion.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Though to me it is&hellip; inelegant. Rough. It&rsquo;s a once in a lifetime craft, I think it deserves at least some sort of planning. Some prefer
it flashy, some prefer it quick, some prefer it painful, but most prefer it slow and progressive.
As for me, well, I decided it must be absolutely unspectacular. Something that evokes no pain and leaves no lasting scar in the
heart of the others. I have the chance to have received a scientific education, and biology, chemistry and physics
can help me to rest assured, I&rsquo;m not afraid to fail or suffer. Though, I know some may weep and I suppose it is a price to pay.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I thought about a location and a mean devoid of any symbol. Nothing should give any hint, any idea about what was wrong.
It&rsquo;s happening, because that&rsquo;s how things are. Unfair.
After carefully designing my moment, I thought I would just carry out the plan.
But I just had to leave a message.</p>
<p>— And you want me to be the messenger?</p>
<p>— Maybe you can carry this one instead.<br>
Deciding on a date seemed unnecessary since I wanted to carry it out immediatly.
But in the meanwhile, I still had to prepare, and for this, I had to carry on for a while.
I surprised myself checking briefly left and right before crossing on my way to work.
It took me by surprise, I thought that it may be temporary, a simple effect of the excitement the planning had on me.
The reality was that I didn&rsquo;t want anything else than the planned way. And this very fact made me care.
It made me care about my body, my health, what&rsquo;s left of my morality and principles.
The only way to start caring was to prepare the ultimate mean to not care.
Nothing should stand before me and the promised release. Health issues are a distraction.
It gives meaning and reasons for someone to go. I don&rsquo;t want this to meddle with it.
I am almost smiling you know. Knowing it&rsquo;s all there, ready to fire at any time.
This very fact made me stonger somehow. It made me face situations in front of which past me would have given up.
I don&rsquo;t feel unbreakable but I feel protected.
I know that whatever happens, the perfect exit door is open.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I don&rsquo;t feel trapped in my life anymore. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I feel free to choose.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I feel free to go on.</p>
<p>Lilli</p>
<h2 id="explanation">Explanation</h2>
<p>Depression, mental illnesses, tough topic. Tough things happen to everyone and somehow, some can&rsquo;t figure out how to deal with it. So they break.
As human beings, they break. Their mind starts acting up and distorting everything around them. This in turns makes them have irrational, twisted views
of themselves, situations, the world. They are not stupid, they are dealing with a greater foe than themselves.</p>
<p>sow_ay is a great artist making very interesting art about mental illness, mostly depression. I hope you don&rsquo;t relate to it ;) It was really great to have these drawings. 
It somehow makes you feel less alone.</p>
<p>So this is an attempt at showing how convoluted, how weird and stupid these illnesses are. The situation can be anything really here.
Who&rsquo;s that messenger? Haaa&hellip; Could be me, could be a psychologist. Could be you. Who knows. Anyone who carries a message is a messenger.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
What do you carry?</p>
<p>The title refers to both the first and the second part, I like that.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I also had fun with the weird sentence full of alliterations. Not particularly pretty or nice sounding, but fun nonetheless. 
That&rsquo;s also a way to say that everything&rsquo;s going to shit.</p>
<p>The warning is, I suppose, perfectly useless, but it&rsquo;s (possibly) important to state that this is unlike other poems about how great life can be I made.
But hey, that&rsquo;s how things are.</p>
<p>So I&rsquo;m happy I had these thoughts out of my head for now. They come and go. Could think you&rsquo;d get used to deal with those, but heh, somehow they always get you.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Let&rsquo;s see who kills the other first.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Cette fille</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/cette_fille/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 23 Mar 2020 00:38:02 +0100</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/cette_fille/</guid>
			<description>J&amp;rsquo;ai cette fille dans ma tête. J&amp;rsquo;ai chaud, je transpire. Mon souffle ralenti et la brise fait osciller doucement ma tunique.L&amp;rsquo;air dans mes poumons est aussi chaud que celui que j&amp;rsquo;expire. J&amp;rsquo;écoute les instructions. Je lui prends les mains, doucement, de sorte que la position naturelle des doigts nous tiennent liés. J&amp;rsquo;entends le son des anges, le son des merveilles et des songes. La harpe m&amp;rsquo;a presque fait sursauter de joie.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="jai-cette-fille-dans-ma-tête">J&rsquo;ai cette fille dans ma tête.</h1>
<p>J&rsquo;ai chaud, je transpire. Mon souffle ralenti et la brise fait osciller doucement ma tunique.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
L&rsquo;air dans mes poumons est aussi chaud que celui que j&rsquo;expire.
J&rsquo;écoute les instructions. Je lui prends les mains, doucement, de sorte que la position naturelle des doigts
nous tiennent liés. J&rsquo;entends le son des anges, le son des merveilles et des songes.
La harpe m&rsquo;a presque fait sursauter de joie.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Et je commence à bouger, lentement. Gauche. Doucement. Droite. Doucement.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Je sens la tension qui évolue dans mes mains.
Mes yeux se ferment avec pour dernière image, nos mains enlacées.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Mes bras sont lourds de chaleur mais mes poils se dressent.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Nous sommes enfin accordés.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Gauche. Droite.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Lentement.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Plus. Lentement.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Sans même ouvrir les yeux, nous plaçons nos mains comme pour une valse.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Elles mains sont moites, nos dos sont humides, la température n&rsquo;est pourtant plus qu&rsquo;un vague détail.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Nous sentons notre chaleur se diffuser l&rsquo;un dans l&rsquo;autre.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Gauche. Droite.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Même la senteur des corps se déplace au gré du mouvement.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Nous ne savons plus qui nous sommes.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
L&rsquo;individualité n&rsquo;a plus de sens.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Il n&rsquo;y a que le son de la harpe, une chaleur unique, un mouvement unique.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
L&rsquo;espace qui séparait les corps n&rsquo;existent plus. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Nous portons les même jambes qui poussent sur le sol, les même bras qui seulement s&rsquo;effleurent sans que rien ne puisse les séparer,
les même seins qui se collent sur la poitrine, le même poids qui se déplace lentement de gauche à droite.
Un souffle lent et chaud vient faire évaporer la sueur sur nos épaules.
Le mouvement se fait plus lent, mais la connexion se fait plus forte encore.
L&rsquo;immobilité au rythme des cordes, le silence du mouvement oscillant qui se propage sans que rien ne bouge.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Sauf que tout bouge à l&rsquo;intérieur.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Le plus subtil des mouvements est un tsunami de sensations.
On attend le prochain battement de coeur avec impatience, la célébration de la vie, l&rsquo;hymne de l&rsquo;être unique.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
La sensation d&rsquo;une tendre caresse sur le dos est une extase qui pleure sans voix.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Le souffle chaud sur les corps nous soûle et nous asservi à l&rsquo;addiction.
Et à se soûler à la lave, c&rsquo;est notre identité qui se consume.
D&rsquo;un feu doux, d&rsquo;un feu qui étreint, d&rsquo;un feu qui rassure.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Un sentiment simple, celui d&rsquo;être assez, celui d&rsquo;être là où il le faut.<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>Doucement le mouvement s&rsquo;estompe, les voix arrivent, il est temps.
La transe se rompt comme un elastique qui claque entre les doigts.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Mes yeux sont éblouis, mais je distingue une expression dont la neutralité ne fait que refléter la mienne.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Perdu, dans le monde réel, sans harpe ni certitudes, je m&rsquo;accroche à son cou, lentement, sans même me rendre compte qu&rsquo;elle esquisse le même geste.
La senteur rassurante de celle avec qui j&rsquo;avais entamé l&rsquo;exercice m&rsquo;apaise.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Et là, un moment, nous partageons à deux le retour au réel.
Une tristesse m&rsquo;envahit, le chagrin d&rsquo;avoir quitté l&rsquo;extase, soutenable seulement par la joie, plus immense encore, de l&rsquo;avoir connue.
Je la regarde un moment avec le sentiment, pendant un moment, de la plus grande vulnérabilité.
Je suis là, devant toi, et tu as touché l&rsquo;essence de mon âme. Je te sens fébrile aussi.
Un simple merci chanté de concert par nos voix comme brisées par mille ans de silence.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
On se déplace, on parle à nouveau, on rejoint le groupe, encore un peu sonné.
Et le coeur comme secoué, la vie se poursuit. Dans quelques minutes ce sera passé.
Tout ça devient &ldquo;c&rsquo;était bien&rdquo;. On ne se souvient plus des instructions, vaguement de la harpe.
Peut-être que je fabule, que ce n&rsquo;était qu&rsquo;un rêve, après tout, une telle extase est étrange, invraisemblable.
Les souvenirs, c&rsquo;est précieux, c&rsquo;est une part de nous.
Comme le sable ils se faufilent et on n&rsquo;en garde que quelques grains.
Comme un rêve, ils s&rsquo;échappent de nos pensées aussi vite qu&rsquo;ils le peuvent.
On sait que nos expériences nous façonnent en tant qu&rsquo;humains, nous font grandir.
Tu penses qu&rsquo;en retrouvant des souvenirs, enfouis, oubliés,
des photos, des textes, on puisse grandir encore?
Finalement si on l&rsquo;a oublié, peut-être qu&rsquo;on peut regarder notre souvenir avec nos yeux nouveaux.
Peut-être qu&rsquo;on peut grandir encore, rien qu&rsquo;avec ce qu&rsquo;on a.</p>
<p>Et un soir de printemps, il revient comme une enclume sur un oeuf.</p>
<p>Lilli</p>
<h2 id="explications">Explications</h2>
<p>Gennetines. J&rsquo;étais à Gennetines, voilà.</p>
<p>Bon, j&rsquo;étais donc au grand bal de l&rsquo;Europe, à Gennetines, et j&rsquo;ai rencontré C, qui m&rsquo;a bien fait marré, on a bien dansé ensemble. Et puis au final on se retrouvait tous les jours, que ce soit pour manger ou danser ou certains ateliers.
Et puis vint la &ldquo;Relaxation valsée&rdquo;. Et c&rsquo;était ça. C&rsquo;était la relaxation valsée. Je n&rsquo;ai aucun doute sur le fait qu&rsquo;on a pas du tout suivi l&rsquo;exercice, on s&rsquo;est juste absorbé l&rsquo;un l&rsquo;autre. En même temps y&rsquo;avait une harpe, ils ont cherché.</p>
<p>J&rsquo;ai beaucoup apprécié mon temps passé avec elle et sa famille. Je ne sais pas comment ça s&rsquo;appelle, pas un coup de foudre mais elle est tombée amoureuse en gros, mais c&rsquo;est probablement le genre &ldquo;d&rsquo;amour&rdquo; un peu fugace. Dans tous les cas, super expérience, elle a clairement apporté une grosse grosse pierre à l&rsquo;édifice Gennetines dans ma vie.</p>
<p>La mémoire étant ce qu&rsquo;elle est, mes souvenirs s&rsquo;apauvrissent. Mais si je me souviens encore de son rire adorable et de son sourire enjoué, je me souviens encore plus de ce moment partagé.
J&rsquo;espère la revoir à Gennetines à nouveau. Enfin, si Gennetines il y a&hellip;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.gennetines.org/en/">https://www.gennetines.org/en/</a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Growth</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/growth/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:24:14 +0100</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/growth/</guid>
			<description>Seed When we see a model in life, we generally tend to try, more or less consciously, to become more like it. Because we see something in this person that inspires us, or that feels so right, that we just want to take even just a piece of that for ourselves. Be it a value, a point of view, a character trait, many things can trigger this phenomenon.Is it his unbreakable determination?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="seed">Seed</h3>
<p>When we see a model in life, we generally tend to try, more or less consciously, to become more like it.
Because we see something in this person that inspires us, or that feels so right, that we just want to take even just a piece of that for ourselves.
Be it a value, a point of view, a character trait, many things can trigger this phenomenon.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Is it his unbreakable determination? The spark of wisdom is her eyes?
His infinite kindness? Her unrelenting passion?</p>
<h3 id="sprout">Sprout</h3>
<p>Whatever might it be, there is something we want to take home, with us, within our very souls. Something that is so gorgeous that we feel our lack thereof.
It&rsquo;s not a feeling of inferiority, it&rsquo;s not a feeling of not being enough.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
It&rsquo;s the realization that we could be more.
That what this person has, that we don&rsquo;t, would make us a better person.
And this fragment of humility, recognizing that someone has something we don&rsquo;t, it&rsquo;s what will make us grow. Letting go of this ego that brings us down. Accepting the world the way it is, accepting who we are, and deciding to do something about it.</p>
<h3 id="flower">Flower</h3>
<p>Ages after, after relentlessly finding new incredible people, after absorbing all their kindness and wisdom, all of their beautiful passion and determination, you end up struggling, with fewer and fewer bits of humanity left to gather.
And at some point, confused and scared, you end up to the wall. Now it&rsquo;s for you to become even better, to grow even more, radiating the beauty of a thousand friends, the wisdom of a thousand strangers, it&rsquo;s your turn to create.
It&rsquo;s for you to continue to nurture these qualities, to find a way to be kinder even than the kindest person, to have more wisdom than even the oldest sage, and  for your smile to warm a million hearts.</p>
<h3 id="pollination">Pollination</h3>
<p>When you contemplate this apparently insurmountable mountain, you are left confused, you are left clueless, wandering through the abyss of uncertainty. Of course, you learned to deal with it. Yet there is still concern to be had. The ominous feeling of forgetting something important.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
You see the eyes of your young friend, watching you.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
He&rsquo;s looking at you with the same eyes you had when you started your adventure.
<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>John Doe</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Winter feeling</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/winter_feeling/</link>
			<pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 13:54:56 +0100</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/winter_feeling/</guid>
			<description>Introduction: It&amp;rsquo;s cold outside. Your nose is hardened by the cold and it starts running. Your fingertips are numb and your gloves don&amp;rsquo;t keep the warmth enough. Your breath creates wonderful volutes that your eyes, squinting through the wind, sometimes contemplate. And you find in your pockets, the cold metal that would deliver you. Your fingers have trouble holding it straight and turning it, but it clicks, it opens, and here you are.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction:</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s cold outside. Your nose is hardened by the cold and it starts running. Your fingertips are numb and your gloves don&rsquo;t keep the warmth enough. Your breath creates wonderful volutes that your eyes, squinting through the wind, sometimes contemplate.
And you find in your pockets, the cold metal that would deliver you. Your fingers have trouble holding it straight and turning it, but it clicks, it opens, and here you are.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I turn a page.</p>
<h2 id="home">Home:</h2>
<p><em>I want to go home</em> you said. And here you are, pushing the door. I hear these familiar footsteps, this familiar breathing. The noise of the coat hanger, the shoes placed near mine.</p>
<p><em>The wood in the fireplace crackles.</em></p>
<p>A warm atmosphere envelops you now. It&rsquo;s still cold in here, but there&rsquo;s another kind of warm. The hot chocolate is next to my tea, waiting for you. As I put down my book, I smile looking at your red nose while you take the plaid placed close to the fire. All wrapped up, I hug you on the couch, all the while adjusting the plaid on your shoulders. Your rub you hands together to warm them up, and then wrap them around the cup of hot chocolate.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I take my book and continue where I left off.</p>
<p><em>The fireplace moans again.</em></p>
<p>As you are warming up, you put your head on my shoulder, your hair tickling my neck. And with the eyes closed, you feel your body going from numb to resting. Your breathing is calming rapidly.
The soft movement of my head while reading, my inaudible breathing, the smell of chocolate. Your adventurous hand caresses my arm, but the cold reality makes it flee back under the plaid. A tender smile rewards your efforts, while your sigh.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I turn a page.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
You smile smelling my scent on my neck and place there a kiss before taking a sip of chocolate. A long breathe. Yellow orange and red were disputing the space on the walls. You gazed around with this calm and posed look, with the eyes half closed, full of appreciation.</p>
<p><em>The fireplace sings.</em></p>
<p>You place your head on my lap. You feel like you belong. You feel like this is where you want to be.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I turn a page.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
As your consciousness sinks more and more, you feel a gentle hand stroking your hair, pushing you further into bliss.</p>
<p>Just before letting yourself leave the realm of consciousness you think:</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<h2 id="context">Context:</h2>
<p>Note: The characters do not have any specified sex or gender. Given the inspiration, it was naturally a man-woman scenario for me, but I like it in any configuration. For this purpose, I removed every gender connoted thing. I had written &ldquo;hair cascading on your cheeks&rdquo;, which, statistically, makes it more likely to be a woman. I replaced it by &ldquo;your hair tickling my neck&rdquo;. It&rsquo;s more &lsquo;bonding&rsquo; and more gender neutral. Please imagine whoever you want. (by the way, the hot chocolate is homemade so you can also make it suit your taste&hellip; with a bit a cinnamon?)</p>
<p>I really like this kind of atmosphere, calm quiet, tender, accepting. You may have noticed that no words were exchanged. The idea sprouted from a friend with whom I cuddle a fair bit saying <em>I want to go home and lie down for a bit</em>. Of course she meant her home, and she meant going in bed and nap or rest. But for some reason, I wanted to be this person reading a book, I wanted to be this kind, comforting presence. I rewrote the whole text I had written in the first place, and I hope it sounds better.</p>
<h2 id="comments">Comments:</h2>
<p>I wanted to show the characters know each other so well that he simply knows what is happening in the head of his companion. Just by her breathing, the way the footsteps resonates on the floor, all the myriad of infinitely subtle clues and cues, he knows perfectly how she feels. Communication happens, but no words.</p>
<p>I had the idea of placing the fireplace as something exterior, that is simply <em>here</em> and simply <em>happens</em>. I created a gradation from very descriptive to highly subjective regarding the fireplace, which also goes with the state of the arriving companion: cold and numb, warming up and calming down, comfy and resting. I also wanted a sort of parallel with the static characted, he&rsquo;s not doing much, his state doesn&rsquo;t change but everything would be so different without him. I thought about making it less obvious that he made the hot chocolate, that he placed the plaid in front of the fireplace. That it could&rsquo;ve been here all along. I think it would actually go against the purpose of this text. It should be simple, easy to understand, because what&rsquo;s important is not about deciphering, it&rsquo;s about feeling, it has to flow. I hope it flows a bit.</p>
<p>Turning the pages was an idea in combination with the fireplace to slow down the pace. The point is to read slowly, calmly and letting the atmosphere sink into you. The funny thing is, when I wrote it, I was imagining myself as the companion character, and imagining how I felt, tired, cold, numb, how I would&rsquo;ve done things, and finally how I would&rsquo;ve described it from someone else&rsquo;s point of view. Actually, I almost started to lie down and sleep. It always gets me.</p>
<p>Stay warm!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Head in the clouds</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/head_in_the_clouds/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 02:54:08 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/head_in_the_clouds/</guid>
			<description>&amp;ldquo;Yes, it may sound stupid but it&amp;rsquo;s been like, years I&amp;rsquo;ve had that problem! And I tried mostly everything.&amp;rdquo;
 &amp;ldquo;Everything?&amp;rdquo;
She wasn&amp;rsquo;t very interested, but polite, according to the social conventions she learned.But she finished her daily tasks long ago, so she didn&amp;rsquo;t need to worry.
 &amp;ldquo;Well, I went to see my doctor first, he said I should get a better pillow. I have an amazing pillow now.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> &ldquo;Yes, it may sound stupid but it&rsquo;s been like, years I&rsquo;ve had that problem! And I tried mostly everything.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;Everything?&rdquo;</p>
<p>She wasn&rsquo;t very interested, but polite, according to the social conventions she learned.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
But she finished her daily tasks long ago, so she didn&rsquo;t need to worry.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Well, I went to see my doctor first, he said I should get a better pillow. I have an amazing pillow now. I sleep much better, that&rsquo;s nice, I even stopped snoring.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;Oh that&rsquo;s something, you&rsquo;re no back to square one, at least.&rdquo;</p>
<p>She reoriented her wheelchair to be able to draw and listen at the same time.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
She is drawing a werewolf on her notepad.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Mhh I suppose yes. But then the doctor said I may go to see a rheumatologist. He checked but apparently nothing was wrong with my problem. He said maybe I&rsquo;m using it too much, but it&rsquo;s not my 2 hours of weekly sport that would do that!&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;And that&rsquo;s all he said?&rdquo;</p>
<p>It wasn&rsquo;t as boring as she thought, he&rsquo;s explaining quickly.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
She was actually drawing the in-between stage, when it transforms.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Ah, of course he made some scans and stuff. The big machine was very impressive. He said I have a begining of arthrosis. But since I&rsquo;m young enough, it should not progress too much thanks to the physiotherapy. Everything else is good.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;Are they just going to bounce you off another specialist all the time?&rdquo;</p>
<p>For some reason, she ended up drawing his face on the transforming werewolf.</p>
<p> &ldquo;I said to the physiotherapist about my neck and she tried her best. It actually helped a bit, but it kept coming back. Though she put my shoulder back in place after my bicycle accident, she did wonders really. Though she said it can be stress, and that this problem should be taken care of before coming back to her.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;You don&rsquo;t look like a stressed out person.&rdquo;</p>
<p>She was wondering how long he would stay. She needed him to stay a bit more for her to draw.</p>
<p> &ldquo;I suppose. The psychiatrist was very competent. He actually helped me get rid of my arachnophobia. But concerning stress, as you said, there&rsquo;s nothing wrong.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;But that&rsquo;s hilarious how no one gives you what you want but you end up with something fixed anyway. So that&rsquo;s the end of the adventure?&rdquo;</p>
<p>She started to like it. She was drawing the tail.
His voice was rather deep, and she found it charming in a way.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Almost. I decided to go to this Reiki person a friend of mine suggested.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;Let me guess.&rdquo;</p>
<p>She was not into that.
But she was very into werewolves.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Yes, basically it did the same thing as the physiotherapist, it went better for the following days and it came back again.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;Did she have any insight as to why this happened?&rdquo;</p>
<p>She was drawing ripped-off clothes now.
She smiled when she imagined what was below his shirt.</p>
<p> &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t really know. She said the energy flowed very well, that I&rsquo;m very open. Whatever that means.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;The energy flows hmm.&rdquo;</p>
<p>She finds his way of looking at her pretty intense, and that sure made something flow.
She decided to draw a big belt to hide her thoughts.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Yes and apparently I&rsquo;d have a sort of energy leak or something, maybe I&rsquo;m not using proper words, I don&rsquo;t know much about it.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;What are you supposed to do about it? Put an energy plug?&rdquo;</p>
<p>She thought a bit of sarcasm couldn&rsquo;t hurt.
She was trying to add some sharp teeth.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Well, she told me to come back. The second time, after the session she said that I should probably eat healthier and be more mindful about it, that it would help with my digestion and make me a more wholesome person, thus helping with the leak.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;So you became vegetarian?&rdquo;</p>
<p>That was her definition of healthy. No one is perfect okay.
She was more and more interested in this new officemate.
And she was adding some muscles here and there.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Not really, but I&rsquo;m more mindful. I care about where the things I buy come from. Actually, it made me gain a real interest in food. There&rsquo;s so many more ingredients than I thought!&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;I know right? Talking about chia seeds, I&rsquo;m here.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Chia seeds have interesting properties indeed.
And so have the eyes she is refining.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Well, actually I noticed that digestion is easier, so there&rsquo;s that. The woman was right. But it still hurts.&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;So there&rsquo;s no solution?&rdquo;</p>
<p>She added some shadows and some more hair.
As she was drawing unrealistically fast for the needs of the scenario, she had to sharpen her pencil.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Not that I&rsquo;m aware of. Oh it&rsquo;s already so late? I&rsquo;m heading out. Cheers&rdquo;</p>
<p> &ldquo;Oh okay. Cheers I guess.&rdquo;</p>
<p>She was surprised how abrupt it was.
She would have liked to hear more. He voice was soothing. And her drawing wasn&rsquo;t finished.
She went to the window to observe him leave. He went past her car. She cannot stand much but her right leg works well enough to drive an automatic car.
She would stay until even later, for she doesn&rsquo;t really have anything else to do.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Where did I put my bike already?&rdquo; he said as he was looking the wrong way.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Ah&rdquo;. He found it. Good job. He put his helm on, turned on his bike light. &ldquo;It&rsquo;s already eleven, why is she staying in the office so late?&rdquo;, as he said that, he closed the door of the bike shed. 
He was out. The air is fresh, but not cold. The wind is calm, waking up for a few cuddles with his raincoat. No cloud to be seen tonight.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
 She was finishing her drawing, and she drew the immense rock in the sky. Bright. He looked up, as everyday, mesmerized by the light, by the creases, by the craters, by its presence.
He couldn&rsquo;t detach his eyes from it. Once or twice he almost missed a red light. He really does have the head in the clouds. But he&rsquo;s used to it, he does that every evening.
Every evening he looks up the sky. And everytime, he feels the warmth of the moon, much warmer than the one of the sun. Like a hug, like a dear friend. Shining on him with all its love. Sometimes he feels overwhelmed and a tear falls on the hard ground of the bicycle road.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
And sometimes he would stop on the bench near his home to watch the moon. The Milky Way, the stars, the nebulas. Here since forever and here forever. Nothing in the sky will change during his life, and he takes his time to comtemplate.</p>
<p>She left everything on her desk. She left the office.
Driving her car along the mountain as everyday. She stops just in front of a very dangerous turn, considering the opportunity. Just above, a big, round, bright circle of faraway. She looks to the cliff again.</p>
<p> &ldquo;Not today old friend.&rdquo;</p>
<p>Finally home, after watching the sky during the 30minutes it takes to go home, he was taking off his clothes and heading to bed after the usual bathroom moment. And as his head touches his pillow he mutters: &ldquo;Aaaargh my neck again!&rdquo;.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/qnP29mg/image.png" alt="to the moon"></p>
<p>Lilli</p>
<h2 id="thoughts">Thoughts</h2>
<p>This guy is kinda weird, talking this much to someone he barely knows. But I think he&rsquo;s minding his own business most of the time.
I like how it begins, just right in the middle of the conversation. I think I did that for an effect of &ldquo;something&rsquo;s happening&rdquo;. Maybe also because it&rsquo;s fairly long, and the idea I had was fairly short and straightforward.
But I hope you&rsquo;re also interested in how this guy is built now <em>wink</em>.</p>
<p>The girl was really into him, but she&rsquo;s obviously not going well. (Just a bit suicidal). She makes me think a lot about someone that used to be a friend.</p>
<p>I relate a lot to this man, watching the moon, for I do the same on the way home. I hope that you, at least, figured what was going wrong with his neck&hellip;</p>
<p>There would probably be some interesting analysis to do like when she is drawing sharp teeth and she was being sarcastic, one could say she was drawing the teeth of the sarcasm. It bites you just like that.
Or how the protagonist is never described by the narration until he leaves, and then even he is joined by her, not separated by a new line. Maybe indicating that they are somehow linked together tonight. More precisely that she is linked to him.
So who&rsquo;s the protagonist in the end? But that&rsquo;s already too much analysis and I see you being glad it&rsquo;s the end of the page. But hehe, there&rsquo;s a lot of text coming up sooner or later!</p>
<p>The image is from the video game To The Moon. Nice. Non-combat video game. Story driven. Nice gameplay. Cool references. Above average soundtrack. 9/10.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Supernovae</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/supernovae/</link>
			<pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2019 00:57:10 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/supernovae/</guid>
			<description>Encore un débat, je sens déjà que ça pétille en moi. Ça gronde à chaque virgule, ça détonne à chaque point. Je navigue dans cette logique, ces prémisses délicates, ces hypothèses fertiles. Le flot de mes pensées vire gré des implications. Les écueils sauront s&amp;rsquo;occuper des sophismes jetés par dessus bord, et chaque biais mis à jour se verra mourir au soleil. Au dessus de moi, c&amp;rsquo;est un feu d&amp;rsquo;artifice qui jaillit à chaque inférence.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<p> Encore un débat, je sens déjà que ça pétille en moi. Ça gronde à chaque virgule, ça détonne à chaque point. Je navigue dans cette logique, ces prémisses délicates, ces hypothèses fertiles. Le flot de mes pensées vire gré des implications. Les écueils sauront s&rsquo;occuper des sophismes jetés par dessus bord, et chaque biais mis à jour se verra mourir au soleil. Au dessus de moi, c&rsquo;est un feu d&rsquo;artifice qui jaillit à chaque inférence. Des images sublimes, ces fracas délicieux se muant en musique dont je ne rate rien. Pas un murmure, pas une couleur, pas une étincelle je ne saurais manquer. Ces textures, ces mouvances, ces tessitures, ces concordances, le ravissement exaltant de la quête de vérité.</p>
<p> Voir le monde tel qu&rsquo;il est et non tel que je l&rsquo;imagine, c&rsquo;est une fixation, une obsession.  Aussi plat que soit mon miroir l&rsquo;information est distordue. Comment inverser la fonction des perceptions pour retrouver le pur état de la réalité ? La logique, les mathématiques mes outils d&rsquo;artisan, mes outils de raison. Je taille les démonstrations pour n&rsquo;en garder que le coeur brillant. Je façonne de solides colonnes qui soutiennent le poids des théorèmes. Je mets au jour les pépites du vrai enfouies dans la terre des superstitions.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
 Qui dit vrai, qui dit faux, voilà de bien insipides questions. Ce qui est vrai et ce qui est faux, voilà ce qui compte. Ainsi l&rsquo;être que je suis se doit de devenir l&rsquo;outil adapté. Ma personne n&rsquo;importe que dans son action, pas dans son identité. Ainsi, j&rsquo;ai du me changer, moi, et me tuer plusieurs fois. J&rsquo;ai tué tous mes professeurs pour tout apprendre à nouveau. La quête de vérité a fait de moi un meurtrier. Ravageant impunément les vallées de la physique, les marécages des conventions sociales et les abysses de la démagogie.  Découvrir et redécouvrir pour que tout soit en moi, je fus maintes fois feuille blanche et maintes fois noirci. Tel le mathématicien se refusant d&rsquo;accepter une preuve d&rsquo;une absolue magnificence tant que chaque lemme ne sera pas énoncé clairement. Et c&rsquo;est bien en peine, car le raccourci est tentant, il n&rsquo;y a qu&rsquo;à fermer les yeux, ou même parfois qu&rsquo;un, il peut suffire d&rsquo;une moue. Et une foi malicieuse s&rsquo;insinue, s&rsquo;installe, et à chaque mégarde elle grignote de la place. Et toi, que fais tu là, à me hérisser les poils ? Mes yeux sont grands ouverts, mon effroi n&rsquo;égale que ma fascination.</p>
<p> Qu&rsquo;est-ce que ce regard qui semble moquer mes feux d&rsquo;artifice ? D&rsquo;où vient cette désinvolte manière ?
Un éclat familier teinte tes yeux, mes pores frémissent à nouveau. Qui es-tu ?
C&rsquo;est alors que tu te mets à parler ! Quelles belles envolées, quel rythme effréné ! Quel art, quelle réthorique !
Mais affublé de mes gants axiomatiques, ma réponse est bien plus un test qu&rsquo;une simple réplique.
Je construis un échafaudage dogmatique sous un draps de logique. Quelques vis piégeuses mais triviales, quelques poutres épaisses mais creuses. Ma curiosité me faisait vibrer tout entier.
Explose pour moi, montre ce que tu as en toi !<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
J&rsquo;attendais quelques bruits, quelques couleurs, j&rsquo;attendais une belle lueur.
Ce ne fut pas de cette ampleur.</p>
<p> De simples mots, honnêtes, sincères, emplis d&rsquo;une bienveillance de laquelle émergeait une certaine douceur.
La confusion suivit. Quel est ce sentiment qui grandit en moi? Que m&rsquo;avez vous fait, suis-je envoûté?
Pas un bruissement, pas un éclat ? Le calme plat.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Les paroles tournèrent une fois de plus dans ma tête.
Quelques étincelles apparaissaient. Quelques crépitements. La brise tiédissait.
Mais le ciel au dessus de moi avait changé. Je frissonnais.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Enfin je comprenais.
Jamais les artifices des Hommes ne m&rsquo;avaient offert ces couleurs.
Les étoiles explosaient.  Les unes après les autres, battant la mesure de leur dernier souffle. Elles composaient pour moi l&rsquo;ode à la vraisemblance, la sonate de la clarté, l&rsquo;hymne du raisonnement, la symphonie du vrai et du faux. Les notes s&rsquo;enchaînaient, disloquaient mes questions, anéantissaient mes assertions.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
 Contemplant les ruines de mes exercices, je découvrais sous le cadavre fûmant de fausses prémisses enroulé du drapé blanc, un petit oeil dans lequel se reflétait la peinture funeste et magnifique du ciel.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/tQBHdhB/m57.jpg" alt="M57"></p>
<p>Des yeux. Des milliers d&rsquo;yeux semblaient me scruter du fin fond de la voie lactée. Comme autant de miroirs pointés sur moi, j&rsquo;y voyais reflété l&rsquo;essence de qui j&rsquo;étais. Mes réflexions fusaient, des noeuds se défirent, des angles s&rsquo;éclaircirent, des incohérences tombaient, .</p>
<p>Joignant les étoiles, je mourais encore dans la plus pure extase.</p>
<p><img src="https://hubblesite.org/uploads/image_file/image_attachment/25409/xlarge_web.jpg" alt="Galaxy"></p>
<p>Lilli</p>
<h2 id="commentaire">Commentaire</h2>
<p>Je commence par les motivations et puis après j&rsquo;explique un peu le sens</p>
<h3 id="donnez-moi-votre-cerveau-euh-sil-vous-plaît-">Donnez moi votre cerveau. Euh, S&rsquo;il vous plaît ?</h3>
<p>J&rsquo;ai écrit ce poème grâce à l&rsquo;inspiration procurée par ma rencontre avec M. M est un fantastique petit morceau d&rsquo;humanité qui me mind blown de façon régulière. J&rsquo;ai toujours voulu mettre en texte ce sentiment étrange de s&rsquo;attendre à pas grand chose, d&rsquo;être un peu confus genre <em>hausse le sourcil droit</em>. Et bim, d&rsquo;un coup tu comprends, d&rsquo;un coup tout est clair, tout explose dans ta tête. C m&rsquo;a aussi beaucoup donné de ce côté là, et c&rsquo;est probablement son absence qui m&rsquo;a poussé à créer ce site. (Oui je reste cryptique, si on peut dire, c&rsquo;est internet quand même)</p>
<p><em>Instant caliméro</em> (c&rsquo;est mon site, je féskejve). J&rsquo;ai souvent été confronté à l&rsquo;incompréhension lorsque je creusait de questions les tympans de mes interlocuteurs. Parfois même j&rsquo;ai eu droit à de l&rsquo;agressivité défensive, comme si je touchais une plaie ouverte, un trésor enfoui ou les petits fragiles d&rsquo;une mère prête à tout. Et face à ça j&rsquo;étais désemparé. Je manifeste mon intérêt ouvertement, je demande des précisions, pour mieux connaître, mieux comprendre, c&rsquo;est en bonne volonté, en toute bienveillance, mais il semble que ce ne soit pas le message reçu. Récemment c&rsquo;est encore arrivé, à mon grand regret, donc ce ne sont pas des choses qui appartiennent au passé. Je comprends que parfois on ne souhaite pas discuter de &ldquo;grands sujets&rdquo; ou &ldquo;creuser davantage&rdquo;, mais force est de constater que j&rsquo;ai du mal à faire autre chose. Parfois on veut juste du réconfort, cracher un peu de venin et avoir quelqu&rsquo;un qui nous dit Haha, oui, il l&rsquo;a bien mérité. J&rsquo;en suis incapable. J&rsquo;aimerais savoir réconforter autrement, car je me refuse à le faire ainsi. Je suis incroyablement mauvais pour ça, quand bien même je me considère un peu empathique. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
J&rsquo;ai fini par comprendre un jour, que si quelqu&rsquo;un fait quelque chose qui nous déplaît, il ne sert à rien de le hurler, car la réponse est en nous. Il s&rsquo;agit de comprendre ce qui nous déplaît précisément. Une fois cela fait, il faut essayer de répondre à la question &ldquo;pour quelle raison cette personne a fait X ?&rdquo;. Il serait fort triste de répondre par la colère à quelque chose qui nous déplaît alors que ladite chose est peut être parfaitement justifiée !</p>
<p>Enfin bon, au final j&rsquo;ai aussi écrit ça pour montrer son importance à mes yeux. Je n&rsquo;ai pas du tout tenté de distiller l&rsquo;essence de cette importance, je voulais au contraire qu&rsquo;elle prenne de la place. J&rsquo;aime bien comment la fin est finalement assez courte. Ça reflète assez bien le fait qu&rsquo;une fois dans une discussion rationnelle, les choses s&rsquo;imbriquent bien les unes dans les autres, mais ce n&rsquo;est permis que grâce au travail et à l&rsquo;apprentissage des outils de la logique.</p>
<h3 id="détails">Détails</h3>
<p>J&rsquo;avais écrit un long blabla détaillant pourquoi telle figure de style mais en fait ça doit être chiant à lire, du coup je vais juste éclaircir un peu le sens, mais je préfère que vous trouviez tout seul.</p>
<p>Si ça vous plaît pas que l&rsquo;auteur blablate sur son oeuvre, allez-vous-en.</p>
<p>La flamme est familière, probablement parce que je te connais huhuhu. En fait c&rsquo;est la flamme de la vérité (ou de sa quête) que le personnage reconnaît (à force de la traquer !). En réalité il ne le sait pas mais une flamme similaire vit dans ses yeux aussi!</p>
<p>Le protagoniste est visiblement contredit - avec raison - par le second personnage mais la réponse allait au delà de seulement contredire (étant donné que c&rsquo;est le protagoniste lui-même qui avait placé les défauts dans l&rsquo;argument)
On pourrait penser qu&rsquo;on ne sait rien de ce qu&rsquo;il a appris, mais en réalité on a déjà tous les éléments. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Débrouillez-vous. (il y a quand même des indices ci-après)</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Un dogme est une affirmation considérée comme fondamentale, incontestable et intangible formulée par une autorité politique, philosophique ou religieuse.
&ndash;Wikipedia&ndash;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Je pose cette définition, juste pour que vous puissiez y réfléchir si l&rsquo;envie vous prend.</p>
<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Pourquoi trouve-t-il un oeil?<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
On a souvent besoin de détourner le regard pour regarder avec des yeux &ldquo;nouveaux&rdquo; un argument.
Prendre un oeil au sol &ldquo;le trouver&rdquo; c&rsquo;est obtenir ce nouveau regard, nouveau point de vue. (par exemple trouver dans quel angle faire preuve de charité intellectuelle).<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>Il se trouve aussi qu&rsquo;il y a un parallèle avec l&rsquo;expression &ldquo;les yeux sont le miroir de l&rsquo;âme&rdquo; mais pas au sens traditionnel.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;Les yeux reflètent les émotions. On peut lire le caractère et les sentiments d&rsquo;un individu dans ses yeux.&rdquo; &ndash;L&rsquo;internaute&ndash;</p>
</blockquote>
<p>C&rsquo;est vrai dans le sens où la flamme familière qui brille dans ces yeux, c&rsquo;est celle de la quête de vérité, qui visiblement ici défini les personnages.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Mais ensuite, c&rsquo;est le contraire, les yeux nous montrent notre propre âme, au travers du prisme des autres.<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p>Ainsi finalement, le personnage aura simplement&hellip; grandit, à sa manière. Une manière que j&rsquo;estime relativement bayésienne dans le sens où il adapte l&rsquo;entièreté de sa vision du monde en fonction des nouvelles informations reçues (il &ldquo;meurt&rdquo;). En termes bayésien, ça veut dire qu&rsquo;il change ses à prioris et ce faisant change toutes les décisions qu&rsquo;il est amené à prendre. C&rsquo;est pas clair, ok, voir sur <a href="https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/hidden/93376982778390/">cette page pour l&rsquo;explication</a>.</p>
<p>Aucune mention n&rsquo;est faite du second personnage une fois que le personnage comprends ce qui se passe, et c&rsquo;est en lien avec le fait que son identité n&rsquo;a aucune importance, le messager ne fait qu&rsquo;apporter un message et le contenu du message lui est important, rien d&rsquo;autre. (dans la vision exposée par ce texte) C&rsquo;est aussi un petit bash discret de l&rsquo;argument d&rsquo;autorité.</p>
<p>J&rsquo;ai choisi cette image de galaxie parce qu&rsquo;en bas à droite y&rsquo;a une étoile qui visiblement ne déconne pas niveau luminosité (ou alors elle est très proche) et je trouvais ça sympa de se dire que c&rsquo;était le protagoniste, qui rejoignait les étoiles. (je crois que c&rsquo;est une galaxie mais j&rsquo;me suis ptet planté!)</p>
<p>Image de M57 (nébuleuse planétaire) et d&rsquo;une galaxie dont j&rsquo;ai oublié le nom, les crédits vont à ESA/Hubble, enfin, je sais pas comment faire ça mais en gros c&rsquo;est expliqué là <a href="https://hubblesite.org/copyright">https://hubblesite.org/copyright</a></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Paradigm change</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/paradigmchange/</link>
			<pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2019 00:27:56 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/paradigmchange/</guid>
			<description>Disclaimer:  This &amp;ldquo;rant&amp;rdquo; is not about whether one diet is better than another on any aspect, it&amp;rsquo;s about how we treat these different diets. Does not mean I&amp;rsquo;m not biased toward one or the other, and hopefully it won&amp;rsquo;t be too problematic to you.
Problem setup  When you go to the restaurant, you need to check that your food is gluten free, lactose free, meat free, cruelty free, fish free, nut free or even other qualifiers.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h3 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer:</h3>
<p> This &ldquo;rant&rdquo; is not about whether one diet is better than another on any aspect, it&rsquo;s about how we treat these different diets. Does not mean I&rsquo;m not biased toward one or the other, and hopefully it won&rsquo;t be too problematic to you.</p>
<h2 id="problem-setup">Problem setup</h2>
<p> When you go to the restaurant, you need to check that your food is gluten free, lactose free, meat free, cruelty free, fish free, nut free or even other qualifiers. It is usual nowadays that a restaurand would have a section dedicated for one or multiple of these specificities. In this &ldquo;essay&rdquo; I will try to challenge the very idea of assigning these kind of labels to food.</p>
<p> People have different and sometimes incompatible diets. Above all else, this is a fact that we must simply respect for the simple reason that everyone should be free to choose to not eat something. This is the assumption upon which the rest is built.</p>
<p> Putting these tags on a menu is a way to indicate to certain specific persons if they will be able to eat this particular dish.</p>
<h2 id="proposal">Proposal</h2>
<p> Wouldn&rsquo;t it be much more sensible to indicate it the other way around?</p>
<p>&lsquo;Why&rsquo;, you&rsquo;d say, &lsquo;it works well like that.'<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Glad you asked.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->Let&rsquo;s take an example:<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Hey buddy you remember this dude that we didn&rsquo;t meet in college?<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->What?<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->You know, the guy that doesn&rsquo;t have long hair, who happen to not wear baseball caps?<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Alternate version:<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Hey buddy you remember this dude from high school?<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Which one?<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->You know, the guy with blond short hair that was taller than you?<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p> Obviously one is more sensible than the other. Because we describe things by what they are, not by what they aren&rsquo;t.
When things are mutually exclusive it works very well to use one or the other.</p>
<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Example:<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Hi buddy, how&rsquo;s it going?<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Not bad, not bad, you?<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->And:<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Hi buddy how&rsquo;s it going?<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ndash; <!-- raw HTML omitted -->Fairly fine, and you?<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<p> Here, no problem because you are either going fine or not. There&rsquo;s no mistake. This is not so similar with food.
Indeed you either do want or do not want to eat something. Yet because people have different opinions for each and every foodstuff (in their good right), it is only fair to let them decide if it&rsquo;s okay by saying what&rsquo;s inside and not selecting some choices about what&rsquo;s not inside.<!-- raw HTML omitted --></p>
<h2 id="argument">Argument</h2>
<p> An interesting argument is scalability. If you say what&rsquo;s inside, everyone can make its choice. By selecting some subgroups and targeting the &ldquo;main focus&rdquo; of this subgroup, every person that has slightly different views or needs cannot necesarily know whether it&rsquo;s good for them. One person, even not knowing any other subgroup&rsquo;s preferences, should be able to choose the food they are okay with.</p>
<p>Another example came to my mind:</p>
<p> Let&rsquo;s say you own a tavern, and there are more than fifty races, all with different eating habits, all with different preferences. Hobgobelins, orcs, humans, elves, dwarves, ifrits, kobolds and more! (it&rsquo;s a very inclusive tavern, and also modern in the sense that they would be at our technology level)<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Because you are a careful owner who wants everyone to get the food they want, you need to label the food in some fashion so that orcs won&rsquo;t eat the leaves that they can&rsquo;t digest, elves won&rsquo;t eat meat and kobolds won&rsquo;t eat the ashes of the ifrits (kobolds are dumb).</p>
<p>Will you say &ldquo;hobgobelin, orc, dwarf can eat this dish&rdquo;, or &ldquo;Fox-person-suitable food&rdquo; ?
No of course, it&rsquo;s stupid, you just declare what&rsquo;s inside, and every person can ask for the dish they want.</p>
<p> And yet the crazy per-category labelling is happening.
Gluten free, lactose free, ketogenic, vegetarian or vegan or even pescetarian or more.
The scalability really shines here, because once the labelling per ingredient is done, it is enough for all possible habits.</p>
<h2 id="counter-argument">Counter Argument</h2>
<p> A counter argument would be that some ingredients of importance may appear sooner or later. This is true, gluten is not an obvious thing to include in the ingredient list. Yet lactose intolerance and gluten intolerance are like allergies in this regard. We can expect that there would be a list of common (and there is!) of common allergens. This list may be updated as the relevant authority sees it fit.</p>
<p> Of course if only different tastes were involved, it would not be so necessary.
But there are medical, ethical, environmental and maybe more reasons to consume or not a given food, and that does not make every food equal.</p>
<p> Some may also say that it is already done on the back of the products you buy (this ignores the restaurant problem). Indeed products have their composition written.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Here we are talking about labelling, meaning having a symbol or a group of symbols that would &lsquo;summarize&rsquo; the relevant informations. Basically what is done at the moment.</p>
<p> Some eating habits also include in their selection the way the product has been made. Fair trade, vegan (it&rsquo;s not just not consuming animal products but not having anything from animal exploitation). So for instance, coconut seems fine for a vegan. WELL it depends. Some coconut is harvested using monkeys to climb the trees and gather coconuts. Even if the monkey is not being mistreated, this is not, strictly speaking, vegan. Some vegan would draw different &ldquo;thresholds&rdquo; for these questions, but it&rsquo;s not the topic at hand. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
 This was a mere tentative to show how being perfectly inclusive seem difficult.</p>
<p> Though, technology could help us with for instance a qr code that would link you to the complete info. But this is a complex system.</p>
<h2 id="even-tempered-argument">Even-tempered argument</h2>
<p>I understand the reassuring feeling that you may have if you are intolerant (or allergic) to something and you see &ldquo;thing-free&rdquo; label on the food. This is perfectly understandable when it&rsquo;s a question of life or death. I don&rsquo;t really have anything to say about it. Especially that suing someone for mislabelling is hard when you&rsquo;re dead (even though corpses are fairly hard too).</p>
<h2 id="a-cultural-problem-">A cultural problem ?</h2>
<p> If in your community, the norm would be to never eat food X (religion is what comes to mind first for me) then the food would be explicitly labeled &ldquo;contains X&rdquo; because this food is &ldquo;not standard&rdquo;.</p>
<p> Hence in a society where eating meat is standard, wheat flour is common and milk the base of most sauces, it seems logical that we ended up labelling it this way. When you enter in a &ldquo;green&rdquo; restaurant, you expect everything to be organic, so nothing is labeled as organic. Some specific foodstuff might not be though and they would specifically point it. Same with a vegetarian-oriented-but-meat-eater-frienly-restaurant. Vegetarian would be what you expect, therefore meat would be labeled as such.</p>
<h2 id="sort-of-an-argument-i-guess">Sort of an argument I guess</h2>
<p> But anyway, is this practice of labelling good, is it bad?</p>
<p>On one hand I would say that it&rsquo;s not so important as long as you end up eating what you want.</p>
<p>On the other hand&hellip;</p>
<p><!-- raw HTML omitted -->Strong opinion ahead:<!-- raw HTML omitted --><!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I repeat what I said before for clarity.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
disclaimer: I said at the begining that it wasn&rsquo;t about which diet is best, and since here it&rsquo;s heavily opinion based, I will heavily bias the way I present the arguments (that I could have done in a diet-neutral way but choose not to).</p>
<p>It does not make sense to put labels &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo;, &ldquo;vegan&rdquo; or whatever else like that on a menu.
What would make sense is &ldquo;made this way with x,y,z&rdquo; then you decide whether x,y, or z is a problem to you or not.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
This would dramatically change the mindset.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ldquo;this contains meat&rdquo;<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ldquo;and eggs&rdquo;<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ldquo;and cheese&rdquo;<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ldquo;and nuts&rdquo;<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ldquo;and cow&rsquo;s milk&rdquo;<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
&ldquo;and was cooked with butter&rdquo;</p>
<p> People would get a much better view of what they are eating. Yes, most people eat meat everyday and close to every meal. I know for I did the same. Okay, you&rsquo;ll tell me that you know what you are eating since it&rsquo;s litterally the name of the dish you ask for. Yes. Though, there is no contrast with no-meat-options, since those are hidden behind their &lsquo;vegetarian label&rsquo;
And since things are labeled &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo; oh why boy, you&rsquo;re not vegetarian, why would you take this?<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
This is damaging. It separates people, as if not being vegetarian makes you unable to appreciate a vegetarian meal.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
 That is at least how I felt. &ldquo;Oh I&rsquo;ll try this vegetarian thing&rdquo; &ldquo;oh it&rsquo;s not that bad&rdquo;. Duh. It&rsquo;s the same food, just balanced differently. Even people eating with me would be surprised like &ldquo;oh you&rsquo;re vegetarian&rdquo;. <!-- raw HTML omitted -->
 The very fact that I thought &ldquo;I&rsquo;ll try this vegetarian thing&rdquo; is a problem, it should not feel like it&rsquo;s from another planet. And we make it this way by labelling things with &ldquo;vegan&rdquo;, &ldquo;vegetarian&rdquo;.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
It&rsquo;s not for someone who belongs to a group, it&rsquo;s for everyone who&rsquo;s okay with eating that. And people most definitely are because that&rsquo;s what they eat all the time, except we switched one ingredient or two.</p>
<p>This is valid for groups that are fully included one in the others.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
In the sense that <code>$ RV \in VG \in V \in OV \in P \in O$</code> with :
<div class="tableNoBorder">
<table>
<thead>
<tr>
<th style="text-align:left">symbol</th>
<th style="text-align:left">name</th>
<th style="text-align:left">Description</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">$O$</td>
<td style="text-align:left">omnivore:</td>
<td style="text-align:left">almost everything edible</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">$P$</td>
<td style="text-align:left">pescetarian:</td>
<td style="text-align:left">$O$ minus meat-related products</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">$OV$</td>
<td style="text-align:left">ovo-lacto-vegetarian:</td>
<td style="text-align:left">$P$ without seafood</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">$V$</td>
<td style="text-align:left">vegetarian:</td>
<td style="text-align:left">$OV$ without diaries and eggs</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">$VG$</td>
<td style="text-align:left">vegan:</td>
<td style="text-align:left">$V$ but no animal exploitation at all</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td style="text-align:left">$RV$</td>
<td style="text-align:left">raw vegan:</td>
<td style="text-align:left">$VG$ but only raw food</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->

</div>
</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Celcius</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</link>
			<pubDate>Thu, 29 Aug 2019 15:27:37 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/celcius/</guid>
			<description>Intro First of all there is one difficult word in there : hearth which designates the floor of the fireplace. To appreciate this poem, I recommend you to look in the vague (outdoors if possible) and do not fix anything at all, just blurry vision, for like 30 seconds. No, not right now, at the end of the intro. Take a deep breath. Now look away and then don&amp;rsquo;t be distracted by anything.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="intro">Intro</h2>
<p>First of all there is one difficult word in there : <em>hearth</em> which designates the floor of the fireplace.
To appreciate this poem, I recommend you to look in the vague (outdoors if possible) and do not fix anything at all, just blurry vision, for like 30 seconds. No, not right now, at the end of the intro. Take a deep breath. Now look away and then don&rsquo;t be distracted by anything.</p>
<h2 id="celcius">Celcius</h2>
<div class="centeredBlock">


You know, they say it's warm.<br/>
And they say it warms your heart.<br/>
And even that some people smile.<br/>
But... My thermometer is broken. How can I find out ?<br/><br/>
I tried to remember the warmth of the sun,<br/>
I think I caught sunburns.<br/>
I tried to remember the warmth of the hearth,<br/>
My eyes were lost in the ashes.<br/><br/>
But nothing makes sense.<br/><br/>
Because when I think about it,<br/>
And I find my tears flowing,<br/>
I know there is more.<br/><br/>
You, who knows everything,<br/>
Could you tell me<br/>
The temperature of a hug ?

</div>

<p>Lilli</p>
<h1 id="manifest">Manifest</h1>
<p>I know, the intro is weird, but I feel like if you just arrive here with all your thoughts and wanting to read quickly the new post of your acquaintance and then be done with it, you&rsquo;re not really in the right mood see why just below.</p>
<h2 id="context">Context</h2>
<p>This poem was made during a fairly dark period of my life. A permanent struggle at the time. I was terribly lacking human contact, be it social or physical (hugs are drugs). I was sick, my mind was barely working. I wanted to share my confusion about how trivial things can become complicated. But in a cute way.</p>
<h2 id="comments">Comments</h2>
<p>Once again, I imagine the character talking to be a little girl (and if it&rsquo;s a mirror of myself, maybe it&rsquo;s the little girl I was always forbidden to be).<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I like the idea of trying to show that things that we take for granted, can be much deeper than at first sight. And for this, what&rsquo;s best than a fresh look on life: children. They look at everything and discover their emotions with the eye of discovery. And from time to time, they point something that we overlooked or had long forgotten.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Even with that said, I find it kind of childish but not in the right way, I&rsquo;m talking about the writer. It feels clumsy. Also I think there is potential for beautiful imagery here, but it could not go out of his brain. Let&rsquo;s be kind to the sick me.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
I think that &ldquo;temperature of a hug&rdquo; is a beautiful image, and it love it. It&rsquo;s saddening that I left it this way, it could have been so much more. Because I didn&rsquo;t want to ruin this image before reading the poem, I called the poem Celcius.<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
Oh by the way here is my inspiration:</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/3NftUsNp8W0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>It is from a mobile music game I love tremendously: <a href="https://www.rayark.com/g/deemo/">Deemo</a>. It made me discover the artist: V.K. (and Mili is fantastic as well) The song is indeed called 擁抱的溫度, or Temperature of a hug if, like me, you don&rsquo;t read Chinese.</p>
<h2 id="side-note">Side note</h2>
<p>Here is the background I used for this page (still trying out features!). I took this a while ago, it&rsquo;s a fancy bokeh effect. The person who guesses how I took it gets uuuh, pancakes. No, it&rsquo;s cheating if I told you already! But I&rsquo;m never out of pancakes to be honest :D. By the way, I find this background way too dim. I need to fiddle with this
<img src="https://i.ibb.co/zxjKBQP/Bubble-Bath.jpg" alt="BubbleBath"></p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>Raymarching</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/raymarching/</link>
			<pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2019 00:20:57 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/raymarching/</guid>
			<description>Introduction I always had a keen interest into fractals, I played quite a fair bit with Apophysis. That&amp;rsquo;s how I created these images:
As you can see, there was also transparency. They look very different on a white or on a black background, you can try (for the first two ones)
Fractals give me a sentiment of infinite complexity, and complexity looks mesmerizing to me. Especially structured complexity, like see how in the Grand-Julian there is usage of symmetry, and also patterns like these circles waving around the red part?</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="introduction">Introduction</h2>
<p>I always had a keen interest into fractals, I played quite a fair bit with <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apophysis_(software)">Apophysis</a>. That&rsquo;s how I created these images:</p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/DRx1nmv/Grand-Julian.png" alt="Grand-Julian"></p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/Fgt4nWm/Piatch.png" alt="Piatch"></p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/th66ZGb/triancore.png" alt="triancore"></p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/qgdm7br/Triangula.png" alt="Triangula"></p>
<p>As you can see, there was also transparency. They look very different on a white or on a black background, you can try (for the first two ones)</p>
<p>Fractals give me a sentiment of infinite complexity, and complexity looks mesmerizing to me. Especially structured complexity, like see how in the Grand-Julian there is usage of symmetry, and also patterns like these circles waving around the red part? Also the symmetry is only an illusion, because looking carefully, the global idea is the same on both side but it&rsquo;s variating, always redefining itself.
I like that, I just can&rsquo;t help it. It&rsquo;s so abstract, so deep, but at the same time it&rsquo;s just a big fat math equation, tailored by myself to unravel its fierce elegance under the form of an image. <strong>takes a deep breath</strong></p>
<p>So it was really nice, but I had no idea how to render fractals. And I didn&rsquo;t care.</p>
<p>Now the time has come. I&rsquo;ve already written my own (crappy) pathtracer so it cannot be so hard.
I understand how raytracing works. But I never had the chance to learn about ray marching.</p>
<p>So I fiddled with python and found some ressources on internet (where else ?)
I wanted to have as few info as possible, and I wanted to solve all the problems myself.</p>
<h2 id="full-program-in-16-lines">Full program in 16 lines</h2>
<p>Guess what?
It&rsquo;s easy.
I&rsquo;m not joking:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="c1">#this is the object list</span>
<span class="n">o</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb">list</span><span class="p">()</span>
<span class="n">o</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">append</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Sphere</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mf">0.5</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.2</span><span class="p">]))</span>
<span class="n">o</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">append</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">Sphere</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">2</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">5</span><span class="p">],</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mf">0.1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.4</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mf">0.7</span><span class="p">]))</span>
<span class="c1">#setting camera parameters, first position, then point to look at</span>
<span class="n">c</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">Camera</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">15</span><span class="p">],[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">],</span><span class="n">fovy</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">40</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">xres</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">300</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">yres</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">300</span><span class="p">)</span>
<span class="n">img</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">np</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">zeros</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="n">xres</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">yres</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">])</span> <span class="c1"># 3channels</span>
<span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">i</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="nb">range</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">xres</span><span class="p">):</span>
    <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">j</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="nb">range</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">yres</span><span class="p">):</span>
        <span class="nb">dir</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">getDirPix</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">cpos</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">pos</span>
        <span class="c1">#index, final pos of the ray</span>
        <span class="n">io</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">rayMarch</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">cpos</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="nb">dir</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">o</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">contrib</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">*</span><span class="mi">3</span>
        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">io</span><span class="o">==-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">:</span>
            <span class="n">contrib</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">np</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">array</span><span class="p">([</span><span class="mi">0</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">*</span><span class="mi">3</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="k">else</span><span class="p">:</span>
            <span class="n">contrib</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">o</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">io</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">c</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">cpos</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="nb">dir</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">img</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">i</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">j</span><span class="p">]</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">contrib</span>
</code></pre></div><p>Of course there are the <code>rayMarch()</code> function and the <code>Camera</code>.</p>
<h2 id="parallel-with-ray-tracing-and-further-explanations">Parallel with ray tracing and further explanations</h2>
<p>Basically only two things differ from normal ray tracing:</p>
<ul>
<li>intersection function does not really exist anymore</li>
<li>objects are represented by a signed distance function</li>
<li>your ray is litterally taking small steps to go traverse the scene</li>
</ul>
<p>The process goes this way:</p>
<ul>
<li>define objects (like spheres) with SDF corresponding to their parameters (radius, position, color)</li>
<li>choose an origin $O_r$ for your ray (like, not too far not too close)</li>
<li>choose a direction $d$ for your ray (straight on a sphere is good)</li>
</ul>
<p>Here, Rey Marching begins</p>
<ol>
<li>then compute the $SDF(O_r)$ for all objects in your scene</li>
<li>take the minimum of it, let&rsquo;s call it <del>Oscar</del> $msdf$</li>
<li>advance your ray of $msdf$ in the direction d (so it is $newO_r=O_r+msdf$)</li>
<li>then you repeat using the $newO_r$</li>
<li>check if the sdf is EPSILON or less, if it&rsquo;s the case then you intersected, report the color value</li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li>EPSILON is here for some more tolerance (floating point errors or stuff can happen)</li>
</ul>
<p>If you do that, you will loop indefinetely so best thing is to impose a hard limit to the distance the ray can travel
Another solution would be to compute the bouding box of the scene (if at all, possible) and to measure the distance from the ray to the farthest point of it. But well, I just use 50, it&rsquo;s a good number.</p>
<p>You can also impose a number of maximum steps, and if the ray is misbehaving, (doing too many small steps) hop, background color</p>
<h2 id="ray-marching-algorithm">Ray Marching algorithm</h2>
<div class="highlight"><pre class="chroma"><code class="language-python" data-lang="python"><span class="n">EPSILON</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mf">1e-8</span>
<span class="n">LIM</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">256</span>
<span class="n">END</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">50</span>
<span class="k">def</span> <span class="nf">rayMarch</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sd</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">o</span><span class="p">:</span><span class="nb">list</span><span class="p">()):</span>
    <span class="s1">&#39;&#39;&#39; sp is starting point, sd is starting direction and o is the list of shapes
</span><span class="s1">    marches in the scene, returns
</span><span class="s1">    * index of Shape intersected
</span><span class="s1">    * last position of ray
</span><span class="s1">    &#39;&#39;&#39;</span>
    <span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">obj</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">d</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">obj</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">o</span><span class="p">]</span>
    <span class="n">v</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb">min</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="n">index</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">index</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">v</span><span class="p">)</span>
    <span class="n">depth</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">v</span>
    <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="mi">0</span>
    <span class="c1">#test against epsilon here and LIM because sometimes it just gets stuck</span>
    <span class="k">while</span> <span class="n">v</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="n">EPSILON</span> <span class="ow">and</span> <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">&lt;</span><span class="n">LIM</span><span class="p">:</span>
        <span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="p">[</span><span class="n">obj</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">d</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="p">)</span> <span class="k">for</span> <span class="n">obj</span> <span class="ow">in</span> <span class="n">o</span><span class="p">]</span>
        <span class="n">v</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="nb">min</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="p">)</span>
        <span class="n">index</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">minlist</span><span class="o">.</span><span class="n">index</span><span class="p">(</span><span class="n">v</span><span class="p">)</span>
        
        <span class="n">sp</span><span class="o">=</span><span class="n">sp</span><span class="o">+</span><span class="n">v</span><span class="o">*</span><span class="n">sd</span>
        <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">+=</span><span class="mi">1</span>
        <span class="c1"># yes I know i compute twice the same stuff,</span>
        <span class="c1"># I added this later and I was too lazy to change the rest </span>
        <span class="n">depth</span><span class="o">+=</span><span class="n">v</span>
        <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">depth</span><span class="o">&gt;</span><span class="n">END</span><span class="p">:</span>
            <span class="k">return</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span>
    <span class="k">if</span> <span class="n">i</span><span class="o">&gt;=</span><span class="n">LIM</span><span class="p">:</span>
        <span class="k">return</span> <span class="o">-</span><span class="mi">1</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span>
    <span class="k">return</span> <span class="n">index</span><span class="p">,</span><span class="n">sp</span>

</code></pre></div><p>Now, you say, that does not make an image!
Of course we need a camera. But that&rsquo;s maths and all, so let me just say that you give the camera a position to be, a position to look at, and boom, you&rsquo;re set.</p>
<p>Now that we have a camera, we call the very convenient function <code>getPixelDir(i,j)</code> that gives us the direction or the ray</p>
<p>Let&rsquo;s say we want a 1080p image, our image is $w=1920$ pixels wide and $h=1080$ pixels high</p>
<ul>
<li>loop $w$ times:
<ul>
<li>loop $h$ times:
<ul>
<li>$d=getPixelDir(i,j)$ ($i$,$j$ are the current loop number for $w$ and $h$ loops)</li>
<li>$p=getCameraPos$</li>
<li>$color=rayMarch(p,d)$</li>
<li>$img[i,j]=color$</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="results">Results</h2>
<p>boom done. Do that and, like me, you obtain THIS:</p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/nkQskTc/first.png" alt="img"></p>
<p>Incredible huh?</p>
<p>Yes, it&rsquo;s shit, but what did you expect? there is no lighting, no bounce of the light. All this is for a real renderer.</p>
<p>okay, let me add the cos term so that it looks like actual balls at least:</p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/PWBG7XZ/3balls.png" alt="img"></p>
<p>I just wanted to see how it works but now, I need to get on the fractal train.</p>
<p>And I have to say, python sucks! It&rsquo;s so damn slow!</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
		<item>
			<title>My Tiny Dragon</title>
			<link>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</link>
			<pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2019 00:08:44 +0200</pubDate>
			
			<guid>https://luvideria.github.io/EnterTheExit/posts/my-tiny-dragon/</guid>
			<description>Text I have a dragon in my room. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Show me your dragon&amp;rdquo; but I cannot. Sadly, it is small, very very small. And it is fast, very very fast. One may ask &amp;ldquo;Then how do you know it exists ?&amp;rdquo; Well it&amp;rsquo;s simple. Sometimes I feel like I tripped over something but no cable, no furniture just a perfectly flat floor, as if it just carelessly bumped into me.</description>
			<content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="text">Text</h2>
<p>I have a dragon in my room. One may ask &ldquo;Show me your dragon&rdquo; but I cannot. Sadly, it is small, very very small. And it is fast, very very fast. One may ask &ldquo;Then how do you know it exists ?&rdquo; Well it&rsquo;s simple. Sometimes I feel like I tripped over something but no cable, no furniture just a perfectly flat floor, as if it just carelessly bumped into me. I regularly sense a peculiar yet very faint smell, like something caught fire. Though after inspection, nothing burnt, no cooking, no worn out cable or electronic device going crazy. It can only be the fiery breath of the dragon, probably roasting its meal. I have no idea about what this dragon eats though. Maybe it picks something from the trash ? Or maybe it steals from the fridge ? I never noticed such a thing, but I suppose such a tiny dragon doesn&rsquo;t need much. A fly or two from time to time may very well be enough for all I know&hellip; One may say &ldquo;Oh but that&rsquo;s nothing, you&rsquo;re probably imagining stuff&rdquo;. I can only tell you what I experience, but I cannot make you experience my feelings. Let me tell you more about the dragon.</p>
<p>When the wind chimes through my shutters and the sky covers itself of its starry blanket as my consciousness fades, I can hear it, I can feel it. Just next to my head, a calm breathing, a warm breeze.
As soon as I try to gather my still sleeping thoughts, it vanishes. I try to place my hand where I felt it but the mattress isn&rsquo;t warmer, the air isn&rsquo;t agitated, it simply disappeared. But it was here.
Once I was sick and I had terrible stomach pain. Going to sleep was awful, I couldn&rsquo;t get rest because of the pain, but couldn&rsquo;t stay awake because I was exhausted.
When the clouds made everything dark and the wind howled its best to free the stars, I lost myself to exhaustion. A soft warmth pressing against my belly, just like a hot stone, perfectly adjusted.
The hard scales heated up by the ardent inner fire of the dragon made for a very regenerating sleep. The sun just began to rise when I noticed that I slept on the back. I never sleep
on the back. I thought it was because of the stomach pain, maybe this position helps. But after testing, the pain is actually more intense when my body is on the back because the whole belly is extended compared to foetal position. I can only think it was to allow the dragon to heal me somehow. My stomach pain was significantly better this day, and although I was not cured, my state was now tolerable.</p>
<p><img src="https://i.ibb.co/4j24jxf/DSCF2229.jpg" alt="img"></p>
<p>I do not need you to believe in my dragon, my dragon is very real for me and I like him very much. I believe he is my friend and in any case I will always welcome him and his friends. But I do not care if someone does not believe in my dragon. You might be a scientist thirsty for knowledge, or a psychologist looking for an interesting case. Maybe you want to capture my dragon and study him, or make me sit and interrogate me. Maybe you just want to prove me I&rsquo;m wrong, that my dragon is nothing but delusions of an imaginative mind. Maybe. But I won&rsquo;t let you kill my dragon.</p>
<p>You are not allowed any experiment. You are not allowed to make me understand what I actually tripped over or that the sound I heard was something else entirely. You are not allowed to make me doubt that the warmth I felt wasn&rsquo;t his. My dragon will live on until he decides to leave.</p>
<p>Lilli</p>
<h2 id="manifest">Manifest</h2>
<p>The picture is from me, during a trip in Belle-île. One of my first pictures of the stars. My fuji x100s in not made for that, and to be honest, I don&rsquo;t like it so much anymore (the picture, not the camera).
I added it when doing the post, more to see how to put images and figure out a way to put them online easily.</p>
<h3 id="context">Context</h3>
<p>When I wrote this poem I was still active on a forum and there I exchanged with people persuaded by astrology, by Christiannism, by a lot of beliefs that sometimes hurt them more than they help. Some of them were very depressed.</p>
<p>I wanted to share a part of my understanding of this situation.</p>
<p>I feel sorry that they need to go this far in the nonsense to find salvation. Yet, they do feel better, some people find in these something that society, psychiatrists or their job do not offer. And that is not their fault.</p>
<p>And this is very good and I am delighted that they find something that works for them.</p>
<p>Yet they start to build a sentimental, emotional bond with it. And as the little girl (I imagine that, but it&rsquo;s sexist, sorry) will outgrow her enthusiastic imagination, they should also outgrow their beliefs. Not in the sense that they should part with them, in the sense that it is not needed anymore. In the state I saw a lot of people (a lot is actually not even statistically sensible, but it&rsquo;s more than most people dealt with) they were like imprisoned by their beliefs. They could not evolve enough to be able to choose if they wanted to live with or without.
This is saddening.</p>
<p>This is a topic (&ldquo;outgrowing beliefs&rdquo;) that I am fairly sensitive to. I think I have a lot of things to think about on this topic.</p>
<h3 id="comments">Comments</h3>
<p>I decided to share this as-is, without modifications, even if I think I could improve it. (It was written 5 months ago)</p>
<p>I like the way it sounds childish, but the end feels off. It does not feel like a child anymore, and it&rsquo;s more all the frustration that was in me that talked. In some sense, I feel like a gradient of childishness in this poem. Maybe that&rsquo;s good.</p>
<p>Very little rewriting happened (I would definitely use different images instead of twice stars : &ldquo;starry blanket&rdquo;, &ldquo;free the stars&rdquo;)
but at the time I had no intention to publish it, so I did not really care.</p>
<p>I wanted to illustrate how people end up getting into these.. fields? esoterism? I don&rsquo;t really know, but you get it: mostly irrationnal stuff.</p>
<p><strong>Confirmation bias</strong>: Looking for proofs that aren&rsquo;t really there, ignoring all the clues that point in other directions
The stone moment illustrate how vicious life can be at giving you information.</p>
<p>It can look like you got better, but actually the night was just nice and the sleep was in the end of good quality. In any case she would feel better and better. Let&rsquo;s not neglect placebo effect that may very well apply here.</p>
<p>There is also this tendency to not use <strong><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Occam%27s_razor">Ockham&rsquo;s razor</a></strong>: she thinks it was to help the dragon heal her that she slept on the back but it could be a misplaced pillow because, while trying to get asleep, she kept moving around, moving pillows, or whatever other reason.</p>
]]></content>
		</item>
		
	</channel>
</rss>
